Basically, this entire roundtable session here is just going to be focused mainly on prompt engineering.
基本上，这整个圆桌会议将主要集中在提示工程上。
Variety of perspectives at this table around prompting from a research side, from a consumer side, and from an enterprise side.
这里有来自研究、消费者和企业方面的多种视角。
And I want to just get the whole wide range of opinions, because there's a lot of them, and just kind of open it up to discussion and explore what prompt engineering really is and what it's all about.
我想听听大家的广泛意见，因为有很多不同的观点，想要开放讨论，探索提示工程真正是什么以及它的意义。
We'll just take it from there.
我们就从这里开始吧。
So maybe we can go around the horn with intros.
那么，也许我们可以依次做个自我介绍。
I can kick it off.
我来开始。
I'm Alex.
我是亚历克斯。
I lead developer relations here at Anthropic.
我在Anthropic负责开发者关系。
Before that, I was kind of technically a prompt engineer at Anthropic.
在此之前，我在Anthropic实际上是一个提示工程师。
I worked on our prompt engineering team and did a variety of roles spanning from a solutions architect type of thing to working on the research side.
我在我们的提示工程团队工作，参与了从解决方案架构师到研究侧的各种角色。
So that, maybe I can hand it over to David.
所以，我可以把话题交给大卫。
Heck yeah.
当然。
My name is David Hershey.
我叫大卫·赫希。
I work with customers mostly at Anthropic on a bunch of stuff.
我主要与Anthropic的客户合作，处理各种事务。
Technical, I help people with fine-tuning, but also just like a lot of the generic things that make it hard to adopt language models, so prompting and just like how to build systems with language models, but spend most of my time working with customers.
在技术方面，我帮助人们进行微调，但也处理很多使得语言模型难以采用的一般性问题，例如提示和如何构建语言模型系统，但我大部分时间都在与客户合作。
Well, I'm Amanda Askel.
我是阿曼达·阿斯克尔。
I lead one of the fine-tuning teams at Anthropic, where I guess I try to make Claude be honest and kind.
我在Anthropic领导一个微调团队，我想我努力让Claude诚实和友善。
Yeah.
是的。
My name is Zach Whitten.
我叫扎克·惠腾。
I'm a prompt engineer at Anthropic.
我是在Anthropic的提示工程师。
Alex and I always argue about who the first one was.
亚历克斯和我总是争论谁是第一个。
He says it's him, I say it's me.
他认为是他，我认为是我。
Contested.
有争议。
I used to work a lot with individual customers, kind of the same way David does now.
我过去与个别客户的合作很多，和大卫现在的方式差不多。
And then as we brought more solutions architects to the team, I started working on things that are meant to raise the overall levels of ambient prompting
然后随着我们团队里增加了更多的解决方案架构师，我开始致力于提升整体环境提示水平的项目。
society, I guess, like the prompt generator and like the various like educational materials that people use.
我想，比如提示生成器和人们使用的各种教育材料。
Nice.
很好。
Cool.
酷。
Well, thanks guys for all coming here.
感谢大家来到这里。
I'm going to start with like a very broad question just so we have a frame going into the rest of our conversations here.
我想先问一个非常广泛的问题，以便为我们接下来的讨论奠定框架。
What is prompt engineering?
什么是提示工程？
Why is it engineering?
为什么叫工程？
What's prompt, really?
提示到底是什么？
If anyone wants to kick that off, give your own perspective on it.
如果有谁想先谈谈，给出你自己的看法。
Feel free to take the rein here.
随意接管这个话题。
I feel like we have a prompt engineer.
我感觉我们有一个提示工程师。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，确实如此。
We're all prompt engineers in our own form.
我们每个人在自己的领域都是提示工程师。
One of us has a job.
我们中有一个人有工作。
Yeah, maybe since it's in your time.
是啊，也许因为这是你的时间。
One of us has a job, but the other three don't have jobs.
我们中有一个人有工作，但其他三个人没有工作。
I guess I feel like prompt engineering is trying to get the model to do things, trying to bring the most out of the model, trying to work with the model to get things done that you wouldn't have been able to do otherwise.
我觉得提示工程是试图让模型执行任务，尽量从模型中获取最大效益，努力与模型合作完成那些你原本无法做到的事情。
So a lot of it is just clear communicating.
所以很大一部分就是清晰的沟通。
I think at heart, talking to a model is a lot like talking to a person.
我认为，与模型对话在本质上就像与人对话。
getting in there and understanding the psychology of the model, which Amanda is the world's most expert person in the world.
进入其中并理解模型的心理，而阿曼达是世界上最专业的专家。
I'm going to keep going on you.
我将继续围绕这个话题。
Why is engineering in the name?
为什么名字中有工程？
I think the engineering part comes from the trial and error.
我认为工程部分来自于反复试验。
One really nice thing about talking to a model that's not like talking to a person is you have this restart button, this giant go back to square zero where you just start from the beginning.
与人对话的一件好事是，与模型对话时你有这个重置按钮，这个巨大的返回零点的按钮，你可以从头开始。
And what that gives you the ability to do that you don't have is a truly start from scratch and try out different things in an independent way so that you don't have interference from one to the other.
这使你能够真正从头开始，以独立的方式尝试不同的事情，这样你就不会互相干扰。
And once you have that ability to experiment and to design different things, that's where the engineering part has the potential to come in.
一旦你具备了实验和设计不同事物的能力，这就是工程部分有潜力发挥作用的地方。
Okay, so what you're saying is, as you're writing these prompts, you're typing in a message to Claude or in the API or whatever it is, being able to go back and forth with the model and iterate on this message and revert back to the clean slate every time, that process is the engineering part.
好吧，你所说的是，当你在写这些提示时，你是在向Claude或API输入消息，能够与模型进行反复沟通并迭代这个消息，每次都回到干净的状态，这个过程就是工程部分。
This whole thing is prompt engineering all in one.
这一切都是提示工程的综合体现。
There's another aspect of it too, which is like,
还有另一个方面，就是，
integrating the prompts within your system as a whole.
将提示整合到你的系统整体中。
And David has done a ton of work with customers integrating.
大卫在与客户的整合方面做了大量工作。
A lot of times it's not just as simple as you write one prompt and you give it to the model and you're done.
很多时候，这并不仅仅是你写一个提示，然后交给模型就完成了。
In fact, it's anything but.
实际上，情况完全不是这样。
It's way more complicated.
这要复杂得多。
Yeah, I mean, I kind of think of prompts as the way that you program models a little bit.
是的，我的意思是，我有点把提示看作是你编程模型的一种方式。
That makes it too complicated, because I think Zach is generally right that it's just talking clearly is the most important thing.
这样说太复杂了，因为我认为扎克是对的，清晰的沟通是最重要的事情。
But if you think about it a little bit as programming a model, you have to think about where data comes from, what data you have access to.
但如果你稍微把它想象成编程模型，你就要考虑数据来自哪里，你可以访问哪些数据。
So if you're doing rag or something, what can I actually use and do and pass to a model?
所以如果你在做rag或者其他什么，你实际上可以使用、做和传递给模型的是什么？
You have to think about trade-offs in latency and how much data you're providing and things like that.
你必须考虑延迟的权衡，以及你提供的数据量和其他因素。
There's enough systems thinking that goes into how you actually build around a model.
实际上，你需要进行足够的系统思考，以便围绕模型构建。
I think a lot of that's also the core of
我认为很多这也是核心原因，
why it like maybe is like deserves its own carve out as a thing to reason about separately from just a software engineer or a PM or something like that.
为什么它可能应该作为一个独立的课题来思考，而不是仅仅是软件工程师或PM之类的角色。
It's like kind of its own domain of how to reason about these models.
这有点像是一个独立的领域，关于如何思考这些模型。
Is a prompt in this sense then like natural language code?
那么在这个意义上，提示是否就像自然语言代码？
Like is it a higher level of abstraction?
它是否是更高层次的抽象？
Or is it kind of a separate thing?
还是说它是一种独立的东西？
I think trying to get too abstract with a prompt is a way to overcomplicate a thing.
我认为过于抽象的提示是一种使事情复杂化的方式。
Because I think, we're going to get into it, but more often than not, the thing you want to do is just write a very clear description of a task, not try to build crazy abstractions or anything like that.
因为我认为，我们会深入讨论，但更常见的是，你想做的事情就是写一个非常清晰的任务描述，而不是尝试构建疯狂的抽象或其他类似的东西。
But that said, you are compiling the set of instructions and things like that into outcomes a lot of times.
但话虽如此，你在很多时候是将一系列指令和其他内容编译成成果。
And so precision and a lot of the things you think about with programming, about
所以精确性和很多你在编程中考虑的事情，
version control and managing what it looked like back then when you had this experiment and like tracking your experiments and stuff like that.
版本控制以及管理你在进行实验时的样子，以及跟踪你的实验等。
That's all, um, you know, just equally important to code.
这些都同样重要于代码。
So, uh, it's, it's weird to be in this paradigm where like written text, like a nice essay that you wrote is something that's looked like the same thing as code.
所以，呃，这种范式很奇怪，像是书面文本，比如你写的漂亮文章，似乎与代码是一回事。
Uh, but it kind of is true that now we write essays and treat them like code.
呃，但现在确实是我们写文章并把它们当作代码来对待。
And I think that's actually correct.
我认为这实际上是正确的。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好吧。
Interesting.
有趣。
So maybe piggybacking off of that, um, we've kind of loosely defined what prompt engineering is.
所以，也许在此基础上，我们可以松散地定义一下什么是提示工程。
So what makes a good prompt engineer?
那么，什么样的人是好的提示工程师？
Maybe Amanda, I'll, I'll go to you for this since you know, you're trying to hire prompt engineers more so in a research setting.
也许阿曼达，我会问你这个问题，因为你试图在研究环境中招聘提示工程师。
What does that look like?
这看起来是什么样子的？
What are you looking for in that type of person?
你在寻找什么样的人？
Yeah, good question.
是的，好的问题。
I think it's a mix of, like Zach said, sort of like clear communication.
我认为这是一种混合，就像扎克所说的，清晰的沟通。
So the ability to just like clearly state things, clearly understand tasks, think about and describe concepts really well.
所以能够清晰地陈述事情，清晰地理解任务，思考和描述概念的能力，这就是写作的组成部分，我认为。
That's like the kind of writing component, I think.
我实际上认为，
I actually think that
成为一个好的写作者与成为一个好的提示工程师之间的相关性并不像人们想的那样。
being a good writer is not as correlated with being a good prompt engineer as people might think.
所以我想我和人们讨论过这个问题，因为我认为有一些论点是，也许你根本不应该在这个名字中包含工程师。
So I guess I've had this discussion with people because I think there's some argument is like, maybe you just shouldn't have the name engineer in there.
像，为什么不直接叫作写作者？
Like, why isn't it just like writer?
我曾经对这个更有同情心。
I used to be more sympathetic to that.
然后我现在想，
And then I think now I'm like,
你实际上在做的事情，人们认为你是在写一个东西，然后就完成了。
what you're actually doing, like people think that you're writing like one thing and you're kind of like done.
然后我会说，你知道，要得到一个半不错的提示，当我坐下来与
And then I'll be like, you know, to get like a semi-decent prompt, like when I sit down with the model, I'll like, you know, like earlier I was like prompting the model and I was just like in a 15 minute span, I'll be sending like hundreds of prompts to the model.
[Translation missing]
It's just back and forth, back and forth, back and forth.
这就是反复的过程，来回往复。
And so I think it's this like willingness to like
所以我认为这是对
iterate and to look and think, what is it that was misinterpreted here, if anything, and then fix that thing.
迭代的愿望，以及思考究竟是什么地方被误解了（如果有的话），然后修正那个问题。
So that ability to iterate.
因此，迭代的能力至关重要。
So I'd say clear communication, that ability to iterate.
所以我会说清晰的沟通能力和这种迭代能力。
I think also thinking about ways in which
我认为还要考虑
your prompt might go wrong.
你的提示可能出错的地方。
So if you have a prompt that you're going to be applying to, say, 400 cases, it's really easy to think about the typical case that it's going to be applied to, to see that it gets the right solution in that case, and then to move on.
如果你有一个要应用于400个案例的提示，很容易只考虑它将应用于的典型案例，看到在那种情况下得到正确的解决方案，然后继续前进。
I think this is a very classic mistake that people made.
我认为这是人们常犯的经典错误。
What you actually want to do is find the cases where it's unusual.
你真正想要做的是找到那些不寻常的案例。
So you have to think about your prompt and be like, what are the cases where it'd be really unclear to me what I should do in this case?
所以你必须考虑你的提示，想想在那些情况下我该如何处理会非常不清楚？
So for example, you have a prompt that says, I'm going to send you a bunch of data.
比如说，你有一个提示说，我要发送一堆数据给你。
I want you to extract all of the rows where someone's name is, I don't know, starts with the letter J. And then you're like, well, I'm going to send it a data set where there is no such thing.
我希望你提取出所有姓名以字母J开头的行。但你可能会想，我要发送一个没有这种情况的数据集。
There is no such name that starts with the letter J. I'm going to send it something that's not a data set.
没有以字母J开头的名字。我可能会发送一些不是数据集的东西。
I might also just send it an empty string.
我也可能只发送一个空字符串。
These are all of the cases you have to try, because then you're like, what does it do in these cases?
这些都是你必须尝试的情况，因为那样你就能知道它在这些情况下会如何反应。
And then you can give it more instructions for how it should deal with that case.
然后你可以给它更多的指示，告诉它该如何处理这种情况。
I work with customers so often where, like, you're an engineer, you're building something, and there's a part in your prompt where a customer of theirs is going to write something.
我经常和客户合作，通常你是一名工程师，你正在构建一些东西，而在你的提示中有一部分是他们的客户将要填写的内容。
Yeah.
是的。
And they all think about, like, these really perfectly phrased things that they think someone's going to type into their chatbot.
他们总是想着这些非常完美的措辞，认为用户会在他们的聊天机器人中输入。
In reality, it's like they never used the shift key and, like, every other word is a typo.
实际上，他们似乎从来没有用过大写键，每两个字就有一个错字。
They think it's Google.
他们认为这是谷歌。
And there's no punctuation.
而且没有标点符号。
Yeah.
是的。
They just put in, like, random words with no question.
他们输入的只是随机的词语，没有提出问题。
So you have these evals that are like these beautifully structured what their users ideally would type in, but like being able to go the next step to reason about like what your actual traffic is going to be like, what people are actually going to try to do.
所以你会发现这些评估就像用户理想中会输入的结构化内容，但能够进一步推理出你的实际流量将会是什么样子，以及人们实际上会尝试做什么。
That's a different level of thinking kind of.
这是一种不同层面的思考。
One thing you said that really resonated with me is reading the model responses.
你提到的一个让我深有感触的事情是要阅读模型的响应。
In a machine learning context, you're supposed to look at the data.
在机器学习的背景下，应该查看数据。
It's almost a cliche.
这几乎成了一个陈词滥调。
Look at your data.
查看你的数据。
And I feel like the equivalent for prompting is look at the model outputs.
而我觉得提示的等价物是查看模型的输出。
Just reading a lot of outputs and reading them closely.
就是要多读输出，并仔细阅读。
Dave and I were talking on the way here.
大卫和我在来这里的路上聊天时提到过。
One thing that people will do is they'll think step by step in their prompt.
有些人会在他们的提示中逐步思考。
And they won't check to make sure that the model is actually thinking step-by-step because the model might take it in a more abstract or general sense rather than like, no, literally you have to write down your thoughts in these specific tags.
但他们不会检查以确保模型确实在逐步思考，因为模型可能会以更抽象或一般的方式理解，而不是说，不，字面上你必须用这些特定的标签写下你的想法。
So yeah, if you aren't reading the model outputs, you might not even notice that it's making that mistake.
所以是的，如果你不阅读模型的输出，你可能甚至不会注意到它在犯那个错误。
Yeah, that's interesting.
是的，这很有趣。
There is that kind of weird theory of mind piece to being a prompt engineer where you have to think almost about how the model is going to view your instructions.
作为一名提示工程师，确实有一种奇怪的心智理论部分，你几乎必须考虑模型将如何看待你的指示。
But then if you're writing for like an enterprise use case too, you have to think about how the user is going to talk to the model as like you're the third party sitting there in that weird relationship.
但如果你是为企业用例写作，你也必须考虑用户将如何与模型交流，就像你是那个在奇怪关系中的第三方。
Yeah.
是的。
On the theory of mind piece, one thing I would say is
关于心智理论部分，我想说的是
It's so hard to write instructions down for a task.
为一个任务写下指令是如此困难。
It's so hard to untangle in your own brain all of the stuff that you know that Quad does not know and write it down.
在你自己的大脑中理清所有你知道的，但Quad不知道的东西并将其写下来是如此艰难。
It's just an immensely challenging thing to strip away all of the assumptions you have and be able to very clearly communicate the full fact set of information that is needed to a model.
这真的是一项极具挑战性的任务，需要剥离掉所有的假设，并能够非常清晰地向模型传达所需的完整信息集。
I think that's another thing that really differentiates a good prompt engineer from a bad one.
我认为这也是区分优秀提示工程师和差劲者的另一方面。
If you, a lot of people will sort of like just write down the things they know, but they don't really take the time to systematically break out what is the actual full set of information you need to know to understand this task.
许多人只是简单地写下他们知道的内容，但他们并没有真正花时间系统地分析理解这个任务所需的完整信息集。
Right.
对。
And that's kind of like a very clear thing I see a lot is prompts where it's just like
这就像我看到的非常明显的事情是，提示只是
is conditioned.
是有条件的。
The prompt that someone wrote is so conditioned on their prior understanding of a task that when they show it to me, I'm like, this makes no sense.
有人写的提示依赖于他们对任务的先前理解，以至于当他们把它展示给我时，我会觉得这毫无意义。
None of the words you wrote make any sense because I don't know anything about your interesting use case.
你写的那些词毫无意义，因为我对你的有趣用例一无所知。
But I think a good way to think about prompt engineering in that front and a good skill for it is just can you actually
但我认为，考虑提示工程的一个好方法和重要技能就是，你是否能够真正
step back from what you know and communicate to this weird system that knows a lot but not everything about what it needs to know to do a task.
从你所知道的事情中退一步，向这个了解很多但并不完全了解完成任务所需内容的奇怪系统进行沟通。
Yeah, the amount of times I've seen someone's prompt and then being like, I can't do the task based on this prompt.
是的，我看到某个人的提示后，常常会想，我无法根据这个提示完成任务。
And like, I'm human level and you're giving this to something that is worse than me and expecting it to do better.
而且，我是人类水平，而你却把这个交给一个比我差的东西，并期望它做得更好。
And I'm like, yeah.
我会说，是的。
Yeah, there is that interesting thing with like, I mean, current, you know, current models don't really do a good job of asking good probing questions in response, like a human would.
是的，确实存在这样有趣的现象，目前的模型在回应时并没有很好地提出好的探询问题，就像人类一样。
If I'm giving Zach directions on how to do something, he'll be like, this doesn't make any sense.
如果我给扎克指示如何做某事，他会说，这毫无意义。
What am I supposed to do at this step or here and here?
我在这个步骤或这里和这里应该做什么？
Model doesn't do that, right?
模型并不会这样做，对吧？
So you have to, as yourself, think through what that other person would say and then go back to your prompt and answer those questions.
所以你必须作为自己去思考那个其他人会怎么说，然后回到你的提示中回答那些问题。
You could ask it to do that.
你可以要求它做到这一点。
I was going to say one of the first things I do with my initial prompt is like I'll give it the prompt and then I'll be like, I don't want you to follow these instructions.
我想说，我给出初始提示时做的第一件事就是，我会给它提示，然后我会说，我不希望你遵循这些指示。
I just want you to tell me the ways in which they're unclear or any ambiguities or anything you don't understand.
我只希望你告诉我哪些地方不明确，或者有什么歧义，或者有什么你不理解的地方。
And it doesn't always get it perfect, but it is interesting that
它并不总是完美，但有趣的是
That is one thing you can do.
这是你可以做的事情之一。
And then also sometimes if people see that the model makes a mistake, the thing that they don't often do is just ask the model.
然后，有时如果人们看到模型犯了错误，他们通常不做的事情就是问模型。
So they say to the model, you got this wrong.
所以他们对模型说，你错了。
Can you think about why?
你能想想为什么吗？
And can you maybe write an edited version of my instructions that would make you not get it wrong?
你能否写一个修改过的版本的我的指示，让你不会再出错？
And a lot of the time, the model just gets it right.
许多时候，模型就是能正确理解。
The model's like, oh yeah, here's what was unclear.
模型会说，哦，是的，这里不清楚。
Here's a fix to the instructions.
这里是对指示的修正。
And then you put those in and it works.
然后你把这些放进去，它就能正常工作。
Okay, I'm actually really curious about this personally almost.
好吧，我实际上对此非常好奇。
Is that true that that works?
这是真的吗，这样是有效的？
Like does the model, is the model able to spot its mistakes that way?
模型能否以这种方式发现自己的错误？
Like when it gets something wrong, you say like, why did you get this wrong?
当它出错时，你说，比如，你为什么会错？
And then it tells you maybe something like, okay, how could I phrase this to you in the future?
然后它告诉你，可能像这样，好吧，我将来该如何向你表达这个？
So you get it right.
这样你就能正确理解。
Is there an element of like truth to that?
这其中有没有某种真实的成分？
Or is that just kind of a hallucination on the model's part around what it thinks its limits are?
还是这只是模型对自己限制的某种幻觉？
I think if you explain to it what it got wrong, it can identify things in the query sometimes.
我认为如果你向它解释它错了什么，它有时可以识别出查询中的问题。
I think this varies by task.
我认为这因任务而异。
This is one of those things where I'm like, I'm not sure what percentage of the time it gets it right, but I always try it because sometimes it does.
这是我不太确定它正确的比例，但我总是尝试，因为有时它确实能做到。
You learn something.
你会学到某些东西。
Any time you go back to the model or back and forth with the model, you learn something about what's going on.
每次你回到模型或与模型反复交流时，你都会学到一些关于发生了什么的东西。
I think you're giving away information if you don't at least try.
如果你不至少尝试，你是在放弃信息。
That's interesting.
这很有趣。
Amanda, I'm going to keep asking you a few more questions here.
阿曼达，我要继续问你几个问题。
One thing maybe for everybody watching this is we have these Slack channels at Entropic where people can add Claude into the Slack channel, then you can talk to Claude through it.
也许对于观看这个的每个人来说，我们在Entropic有这些Slack频道，人们可以把Claude添加到Slack频道中，然后你可以通过它与Claude交谈。
And Amanda has a Slack channel that a lot of people follow of her interactions with Claude.
阿曼达有一个Slack频道，很多人关注她与Claude的互动。
And one thing that I see you always do in there, which you probably do the most of anyone at Anthropic, is use the model to help you in a variety of different scenarios.
我看到你在里面总是做的一件事，可能是Anthropic中做得最多的，就是利用模型帮助你处理各种不同的场景。
I think you put a lot of trust into the model in the research setting.
我认为你在研究环境中对模型投入了很多信任。
Curious how you've developed those intuitions for when to trust the model.
我很好奇你是如何发展出这些在何时信任模型的直觉的。
Is that just a matter of usage, experience, or is it something else?
这只是使用、经验的问题，还是其他什么？
I think I don't trust the model ever, and then I just hammer on it.
我觉得我从来不信任模型，然后我就不断试探它。
So I think the reason why you see me do that a lot is that that is like me being like, can I trust you to do this task?
所以我认为你看到我这样做的原因是，这就像我在问，能否信
Because there's some things, you know, models are kind of strange if you go slightly out of distribution, like, you know, like, you just go into areas where they haven't been trained or they're kind of unusual.
[Translation missing]
Sometimes you're like, oh, actually, you're much less reliable here, even though it's a fairly, like, simple task.
有时候你会想，哦，实际上，在这方面它的表现远不如我所期望的，尽管这是一项相对简单的任务。
I think that's happening less and less over time as models get better, but you want to make sure you're not in that kind of space.
我认为随着模型的不断改进，这种情况正在越来越少，但你仍然要确保自己不陷入这种境地。
So yeah, I don't think I trust it by default, but I think in ML, people often want to look across really large data sets.
所以是的，我不认为我会默认信任它，但我觉得在机器学习中，人们往往希望查看非常大的数据集。
And I'm like, when does it make sense to do that?
我就想，什么时候这样做才有意义？
And I think the answer is when you get relatively low signal from each data point, you want to look across many, many data points.
我认为答案是，当你从每个数据点获取的信号相对较低时，你希望查看许多数据点。
Because you basically want to get rid of the noise.
因为你基本上是想消除噪音。
With a lot of prompting tasks, I think you actually get really high signal from each query.
在许多提示任务中，我认为你实际上从每个查询中获得了非常高的信号。
And so if you have a really well-constructed set of a few hundred prompts, that I think can be much more signal than thousands that aren't as well-crafted.
所以如果你有一组构建得非常好的几百个提示，我认为这比几千个构建得不那么好的提示产生更多的信号。
And so I think
所以我认为
I do think I can trust the model if I look at 100 outputs of it, and it's really consistent, and I know that I've constructed those to basically figure out all of the edge cases and all of the weird things that the model might do, strange inputs, et cetera.
如果我查看它的100个输出，并且它们非常一致，我知道我构建了这些以基本上涵盖所有边缘案例和模型可能会处理的奇怪输入等等，我确实认为我可以信任模型。
I trust that probably more than a much more loosely constructed set of several thousand.
我可能更信任这个，而不是一组构建得更松散的几千个。
I think in ML, a lot of times the signals are numbers.
我认为在机器学习中，很多时候信号是数字。
Did you predict this thing right or not?
你是否正确预测了这个事情？
And it'd be like looking at the log probs of a model and trying to intuit things, which you can do, but it's kind of sketchy.
这就像查看模型的对数概率并试图直观理解一些东西，虽然你可以这样做，但这有点不靠谱。
I feel like the fact that models output, more often than not, a lot of stuff, like words and things, there's just fundamentally so much to learn between the lines of what it's writing and why and how.
我觉得模型输出的事实，往往是大量的信息，比如单词和其他东西，根本上有太多东西可以在它所写的内容之间学习，以及原因和方式。
And that's part of what it is.
这就是它的部分内容。
It's not just, did it get the task right or not?
这不仅仅是，它是否完成了任务。
It's like, how did it get there?
而是，它是如何到达这个结果的？
How was it thinking about it?
它是如何思考这个问题的？
What steps did it go through?
它经历了哪些步骤？
You learn a lot about what is going on.
你可以了解到很多事情。
Or at least you can try to get a better sense, I think.
或者至少你可以尝试更好地理解，我认为。
But that's where a lot of information comes from to me, is by reading the details of what came out, not just the result.
但对我来说，很多信息来自于阅读输出的细节，而不仅仅是结果。
I think also the very best of prompting can kind of make the difference between a failed and a successful experiment.
我认为，最好的提示实际上可以在失败和成功的实验之间产生差异。
So sometimes I can get annoyed if people don't focus enough on the prompting component of their experiment because I'm like, this can in fact be like the difference between like 1% performance in the model or 0.1%.
所以有时候，如果人们不够专注于他们实验的提示组件，我可能会感到恼火，因为我觉得，这实际上可以是模型性能在1%和0.1%之间的差异。
in such a way that your experiment doesn't succeed if it's at top 5% model performance, but it does succeed if it's at top 1% or top 0.1%.
这样一来，如果你的实验在前5%的模型性能上不成功，但如果在前1%或前0.1%上就成功了。
And then I'm like, if you're going to spend time over like coding your experiment really nicely, but then just like not spend time on the prompt, that doesn't, I don't know, that doesn't make sense to me.
然后我想，如果你要花时间好好编码你的实验，但却没有花时间在提示上，这对我来说没有意义。
Cause I'm like, that can be the difference between life and death of your experiment.
因为我觉得，这可能是你实验生死之间的差异。
Yeah.
是的。
And with the deployment too.
而且在部署上也是如此。
Yeah.
是的。
It's so easy to, oh, we can't ship this.
这很容易，哦，我们不能发布这个。
And then you change the prompt around and suddenly it's working.
然后你改变提示，突然之间它就有效了。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a bit of a double edged sword though, because I feel like there's like a little bit of prompting where there's always like this mythical better prompt that's going to solve my thing on the horizon.
这有点像双刃剑，因为我觉得总是存在一些提示，总有一个神秘的更好提示在地平线上，能够解决我的问题。
Yeah.
是的。
I see a lot of people get stuck in the like mythical prompt on the horizon that if I just like keep grinding, keep grinding, like just not, it's like never bad to grind a little bit on prompt.
我看到很多人被困在那种神秘的提示中，他们觉得如果我继续努力、继续努力，就会找到。
Like you learn, as we've talked, like you learn things, but.
你学到东西，正如我们所谈的，你会学到东西，但。
It's one of the scary things about prompting is that there's like this whole world of unknown What heuristics do you guys have for like when something like is possible versus like not possible?
提示的一个可怕之处在于，有一个未知的世界。你们有什么启发式的方法来判断某事是否可能？
With a perfect prompt whatever that might be.
有一个完美的提示，无论那可能是什么。
I think I'm usually checking for whether the model kind of gets it so I think for things where I just don't think a prompt is going to help I
我通常会检查模型是否理解，所以我认为对于那些我认为提示无助的事情，我
There is a little bit of grinding, but often it just becomes really clear that it's not close or something.
确实有一点努力，但通常很明显它根本不接近什么。
I think that if, yeah, I don't know if that's a weird one where I'm just like, yeah.
我觉得是的，我不知道这是否有点奇怪，反正就是这样。
If the model just clearly can't do something, I won't grind on it for too long.
如果模型显然做不到某些事情，我不会在上面纠缠太久。
This is where you can evoke how it's thinking about it, and you can ask it how it's thinking about it and why.
这时你可以引导它思考的方式，你可以问它是如何思考的，以及为什么。
And you can kind of get a sense of, is it thinking about it right?
你可以有一种感觉，它是否在正确地思考这个问题？
Are we even in the right zip code of this being right?
我们是否在正确的
And you can get a little bit of like a kneeling on that front of like, I'm like, at least I feel like I'm making progress towards getting something closer to right.
[Translation missing]
Where there's just some tasks where you really don't get anywhere closer to like, it's thought process just like every tweak you make just like veers off in a completely different, very wrong direction.
And I just tend to abandon those.
[Translation missing]
I don't know.
我不知道。
Those are so rare now though, and I get really angry at the model when I discover them because that's how rare they are.
不过现在这种情况非常少见，当我发现它们时，我真的会对模型感到非常愤怒，因为它们实在是太稀有了。
I get furious.
我会感到非常愤怒。
I'm like, how dare there be a task that you can't just do if I just push you in the right direction.
我就想，怎么可能有一个任务你不能做，只要我稍微引导一下。
I had my thing with Claude plays Pokemon recently, and that was like one of the rare times.
我最近和Claude一起玩宝可梦，那是非常少见的时刻之一。
Can you explain that just for people?
你能为大家解释一下吗？
I think that's really cool.
我觉得这真的很酷。
I did a bit of an experiment where I hooked Clawed up to a Game Boy emulator and tried to have it play the game Pokemon Red, like the OG Pokemon.
我做了一个实验，把Claude连接到Game Boy模拟器上，试图让它玩《宝可梦红版》，就是最初的宝可梦。
And it's like, you know, think what you want to do.
它就像，你知道，想想你想做的事情。
And it could write some code to press buttons and stuff like that.
它可以写一些代码来按按钮之类的。
Pretty basic.
相当基础。
And I tried a bunch of different very complex prompting layouts.
我尝试了许多不同的非常复杂的提示布局。
But you just get into certain spots where it just, like...
但是你总会走到某些地方，它就是...
really couldn't do it.
真的做不到。
So, like, showing it a screenshot of a Game Boy, it just really couldn't do.
所以，像给它展示一张Game Boy的截图，它真的无法做到。
And it just, like, so deeply, because I'm so used to it being, like, able to do something, mostly.
这让我感到非常失望，因为我习惯于它大多数情况下能做点什么。
And it's so, and I spent, like, a whole weekend trying to write better and better prompts to get it to, like, really understand this Game Boy screen.
我花了整个周末试图写出越来越好的提示，让它真正理解这个Game Boy屏幕。
And I got, like, incrementally better so that it was only terrible instead of, like, completely no signal.
而我得到了逐步的改善，所以它只是糟糕而不是完全没有信号。
Like, you could get from, like, no signal to some signal.
就像你可以从没有信号到有一些信号。
But it was like, I don't know, at least this is like elicited for me.
但我觉得，至少这对我来说是有启发的。
Once I put a weekend of time in and I got from no signal to some signal, but not nowhere close to good enough, I'm like, I'm just gonna wait for the next one.
一旦我花了一个周末的时间，从没有信号到有一些信号，但还远远不够好，我就想，我就等下一个模型吧。
I'm just gonna wait for another model.
我就等另一个模型。
I could grind on this for four months and the thing that would come out is another model.
我可以在这上面磨蹭四个月，最终出来的也只是另一个模型。
And that's a better use of my time to just sit and wait to do something else in the meanwhile.
而且这种等待的时间更好用来做其他事情。
I mean, that's an inherent tension we see all the time.
我是说，这是一种我们一直看到的固有张力。
And maybe we can get to that in a sec, Zach, if you want to go.
如果你想去的话，Zach，我们也许可以稍后再谈这个。
Something I liked about your prompt with Pokemon, where you got the best that you did get, was the way that you explained to the model that it is in the middle of this Pokemon game and here's how the things are going to be represented.
我喜欢你在宝可梦中的提示，尤其是你向模型解释它正处于这个宝可梦游戏中，以及事情将如何呈现。
I think you actually represented it in two different ways, right?
我觉得你实际上用两种不同的方式描述了这一点，对吧？
I did.
我是的。
What I ended up doing, it was obnoxious, but I superimposed a grid over the image.
我最终做的事情是，虽然这很烦人，但我在图像上叠加了一个网格。
Then I had it describe each segment of the grid in visceral detail.
然后我让它详细描述网格的每个部分。
Then I had it reconstruct that into an ASCII map.
然后我让它将这些信息重构成一个ASCII地图。
and I gave it as much detail as I could.
我尽可能地给它提供了更多细节。
The player character is always at location 4, 5 on the grid and stuff like that.
玩家角色始终位于网格的4, 5位置等等。
You can slowly build up information.
你可以慢慢地积累信息。
I think it's actually a lot like prompting, but I just hadn't done it with images before where sometimes
我觉得这实际上很像提示，但我之前从未用图像这样做过，有时
my intuition for what you need to tell a model about text is a lot different from what you need to tell a model about images.
我对文本模型需要告诉它的事情的直觉与对图像模型需要告诉它的事情相差很大。
I found a surprisingly small number of my intuitions about text have transferred to image.
我发现我的直觉中关于文本的惊人地很少转移到图像上。
I found that multi-shot prompting is not as effective for images and text.
我发现多次提示在图像和文本上并不那么有效。
I'm not really sure.
我不是很确定。
You can have theoretical explanations about why.
你可以有理论解释为什么。
Maybe there's fewer of it in the training data, fewer examples of that.
也许训练数据中这种情况较少，示例较少。
Yeah, I know when we were doing the original explorations with prompting multimodal, we really couldn't get it to noticeably work.
是的，我知道当我们进行原始的多模态提示探索时，我们真的无法让它明显地工作。
You just can't seem to improve Claude's actual visual acuity in terms of what it picks up within an image.
你似乎无法改善Claude在图像中所识别的实际视觉敏锐度。
Anyone here has any like ways that they've not seen that feature But it seems like that's kind of similar with like the Pokemon thing where it's trying to interpret this thing No matter how much you throw prompts at it, like it just won't pick up that ash is in that location Yeah I guess like to be visceral about this like I could eventually get it so they could like most often tell me where a wall was yeah and most often tell me where the character was it'd be off by a little bit and
这里有没有人有一些他们没有见过的特征，但似乎这和宝可梦的事情有些相似，无论你给它多少提示，它就是无法识别出小智在那个位置。
But then you get to a point, and this is maybe coming back to knowing when you can't do it.
是的，我想要生动一点地说，我最终能够让它较为准确地告诉我墙在哪里，以及角色在哪里，虽然有些偏差。
It would describe an NPC, and to play a game well, you need to have some sense of continuity.
但然后你会达到一个点，这也许回到了解何时无法做到。
Like, have I talked to this NPC before?
它会描述一个NPC，而要好好玩一个游戏，你需要对连续性有一定的了解。
Without that like you really don't there's nothing you can do you're just gonna keep talking to the NPC because like well Maybe this is a different NPC.
比如，我之前是否和这个NPC交谈过？
Mm-hmm, but like I would try very hard to get it to describe an NPC and it's like it's a person They weren't wearing a hat and it's like you grind for a while like inflate it to 3,000 X and crop it to just the NPC and it's like I have no idea what this is and it's like I ground like I showed it this like
如果没有，那你真的没办法，你只会不断地和NPC交谈，因为你会想，也许这个是不同的
clear female NPC thing enough times and it just got nowhere close to it.
清晰的女性NPC的提示尝试了很多次，但结果依然不尽如人意。
And it's like, yeah, that's just, this is a complete lost cause.
就像，是的，这真的是一个完全的失落事业。
Wow.
哇。
Okay.
好的。
I really want to try this now.
我现在真的想试试这个。
I'm just imagining all the things I would try.
我在想象我会尝试的所有事情。
Like, I don't know, I want you to imagine this, like, uh, this game art as a, as a real human and just describe to me what they're like, what do they look like as they look in the mirror and then just like see what happens.
就像，我不知道，我希望你想象这个，比如说，这个游戏艺术作为一个真实的人，描述一下他们是什么样的，他们在镜子前看起来怎么样，然后看看会发生什么。
I tried a lot of things.
我尝试了很多事情。
The eventual prompt was telling Quad it was a screen reader for a blind person, which I don't know if that helped, but it felt right.
最终的提示是告诉Quad这是一个为盲人设计的屏幕阅读器，我不知道这是否有帮助，但感觉是对的。
So I kind of stuck with that.
所以我就坚持这个。
That's an interesting point.
这是个有趣的观点。
I actually want to go into this a little bit because this is one of the most famous prompting tips, right, is to tell the language model that they are some persona or some role.
我实际上想深入探讨一下，因为这是最著名的提示技巧之一，对吧，就是告诉语言模型他们是某种角色或身份。
I feel like I see mixed results.
我觉得我看到的结果是参差不齐的。
Maybe this worked a little bit better in previous models and maybe not as much anymore.
也许在以前的模型中效果稍好一些，而现在可能不太好。
Amanda, I see you all the time be very honest with the model, like about the whole situation.
阿曼达，我看到你总是非常坦诚地对待模型，关于整个情况。
Like, oh, I am an AI researcher and I'm doing this experiment.
就是，哦，我是一个AI研究员，我在做这个实验。
I'll tell it who I am.
我会告诉它我是谁。
Yeah.
是的。
I'll give it my name, be like, here's who you're talking to.
我会告诉它我的名字，像是，告诉你我是谁。
Right.
对。
Do you think that level of honesty, instead of like lying to the model or like forcing it to like, you know, I'm going to tip you $500.
你认为这种诚实的程度，而不是对模型撒谎或者强迫它，像是，你知道，我要给你小费500美元。
Is there,
有没有，
one method that's preferred there or just what's your intuition on that?
一种更偏好的方法，或者说你对此的直觉是什么？
Yeah, I think as models are more capable and understand more about the world, I guess I just don't see it as necessary to lie to them.
是的，我认为随着模型变得更强大，更能理解世界，我想我就不觉得有必要对它们撒谎。
I mean, I also don't like lying to the models just because, you know, I don't like lying generally.
我也是不喜欢对模型撒谎，因为，我一般不喜欢撒谎。
But part of me is like, if you are, say, constructing it, suppose you're constructing an eval data set for a machine learning system or for a language model, that's very different from constructing a quiz for some children.
但我有些想法，如果你在构建，例如，你在为一个机器学习系统或语言模型构建评估数据集，这和为一些孩子构建测验是非常不同的。
And so when people would do things like, I am a teacher trying to figure out questions for a quiz, I'm like, the model knows what language model evals are.
所以当人们做一些事情，比如，我是一个老师，试图为测验找问题时，我想，模型知道什么是语言模型评估。
If you ask it about different evals, it can tell you, and it can give you made up examples of what they look like, because these things are like,
如果你问它不同的评估，它可以告诉你，并且可以给你虚构的例子，它们是什么样的，因为这些东西就像，
they understand them, they're on the internet.
它们理解这些东西，它们在互联网上。
And so I'm like, I'd much rather just target the actual task that I have.
所以我想，我宁愿直接针对我实际要做的任务。
So if you're like, I want you to construct questions that look a lot like an evaluation of a language model.
所以如果你说，我希望你构建一些看起来很像语言模型评估的问题。
It's just like, it's that whole thing of clear communication.
就是，这完全是清晰沟通的问题。
I'm like, that is in fact the task I want to do.
我想，这实际上就是我想做的任务。
So why would I pretend to you that I want to do some unrelated or only tangentially related task and then expect you to somehow do better at the task that I actually want you to do?
那么，为什么我会假装我想做一些无关或仅仅相关的任务，然后期望你以某种方式在我实际上想让你做的任务上表现得更好呢？
We don't do this with employees.
我们对员工不这样做。
I wouldn't go to someone that worked with me and be like,
我不会对和我一起工作的人说，
You are a teacher, and you're trying to quiz your students.
你是一个老师，你在试图给你的学生测验。
I'd be like, hey, are you making that e-mail?
我会说，嘿，你在做那个电子邮件吗？
Maybe it's a heuristic from there where I'm like, if they understand the thing, just ask them to do the thing that you want.
也许从那儿得到的一个启示是，我想，如果他们理解这个事情，就让他们去做你想要的事情。
I see this so much.
我经常看到这种情况。
I guess to push back a little bit, I have found cases where
我想稍微反驳一下，我发现有些情况下
Not exactly lying, but giving it a metaphor for how to think about it could help in the same way that sometimes I might not understand how to do something and someone's like, imagine that you were doing this, even though I know I'm not doing it.
并不是完全撒谎，但给它一个隐喻来思考可能会有所帮助，就像有时我可能不明白如何做某事，有人会说，想象一下你在做这个，尽管我知道我并没有在做。
The one that comes to mind for me is I was trying to have Quad say whether an image of a chart or a graph is good or not.
我想到的一个例子是，我试图让Quad判断一个图表或图形的图像是否好。
Is it high quality?
它是高质量的吗？
And the best prompt that I found for this was asking the model what grade it would give the chart if it were submitted as a high school
我发现的最佳提示是问模型，如果这作为一个高中作业提交，它会给这个图表打多少分。
assignment.
所以这并不是在说，你是一名高中老师，你知道，这更像是，你知道，这就是我希望你提供的分析类型，就像老师使用的评分标准和我希望你使用的标准相似，或者，
So it's not exactly saying like, you are a high school teacher, you know, it's more like, you know, this is the kind of analysis that like, I'm looking from for you, like the scale that a teacher would use is like similar to the scale that like, I want you to use or,
但我认为这些隐喻仍然很难想出来。
But I think those metaphors are pretty hard to still come up with.
你常常看到的默认是找到某种任务的副本，某种非常类似的任务，
The default you see all the time is finding some facsimile of the task, something that's a very similar-ish task, like saying you're a teacher.
[Translation missing]
And you actually just lose a lot in the nuance of what your product is.
I see this so much in enterprise prompts where people...
我在企业提示中经常看到这种情况，人们...
write something similar because they have this intuition that it's something the model has seen more of, maybe.
写一些类似的内容，因为他们有这种直觉，认为这是模型见过的更多内容，可能。
Like it's seen more high school quizzes than it has LLM evals.
比如说它见过更多的高中测验，而不是 LLM 评估。
And that may be true, but to your point, as the models get better, I think just trying to be very prescriptive about exactly the situation they're in, I give people that advice all the time.
这可能是对的，但正如你所说，随着模型的进步，我认为尝试非常明确地描述他们所处的具体情况，我常常给人们这样的建议。
Which isn't to say that I don't think
这并不是说我不认为
To the extent that it is true, that thinking about it the way that someone would grade a chart as how they would grade a high school chart, maybe that's true.
在某种程度上，这确实是，考虑到某人如何评估图表，就像他们如何评估高中图表，可能是对的。
But it's awkwardly the shortcut people use a lot of times to try to get what happens.
但这常常是人们用来尝试理解发生了什么的一个尴尬捷径。
So I'll try to give someone that I can actually talk about, because I think it's somewhat interesting.
所以我会试着给某个我能真正谈论的人，因为我觉得这有点有趣。
So writing, you are a helpful assistant writing a draft of a document, right?
所以写道，你是一个有帮助的助手，正在撰写文档的草稿，对吧？
It's not quite what you are.
这并不完全是你。
You are in this product.
你在这个产品中。
If you're writing an assistant that's in a product, tell me I'm in the product.
如果你是在一个产品中写助手，告诉我我在这个产品中。
Tell me I'm writing on behalf of this company.
告诉我我代表这家公司在写。
I'm embedded in this product.
我嵌入在这个产品中。
I'm the support chat window on that product.
我是那个产品的支持聊天窗口。
You're a language model.
你是一个语言模型。
You're not a human, that's fine.
你不是人，这没关系。
But just being really prescriptive about the exact context about where something is being used.
但对所使用的确切上下文非常明确。
I found a lot of that because I guess my concern most often with role prompting is people use it as a shortcut.
我发现很多这样的情况，因为我想我对角色提示的最大担忧是人们把它当作捷径使用。
of a similar task they want the model to do, and then they're surprised when Quad doesn't do their task right.
去做他们希望模型完成的类似任务，然后当 Quad 没有正确完成他们的任务时，他们很惊讶。
But it's not the task.
但这不是任务。
You told it to do some other task.
你告诉它去做其他任务。
And if you didn't give it the details about your task, I feel like you're leaving something on the table.
如果你没有给它关于你的任务的细节，我觉得你留下了一些机会。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It does feel like a thing, though, to your point of as the models scale.
不过，确实感觉到这一点，正如你所说，随着模型的扩展。
Like, maybe in the past it was true that they only really had a strong understanding of
就像，也许在过去，确实只有在理解
elementary school tests comparatively, but as they get smarter and can differentiate more topics, I don't know, just like being queer.
小学测试方面相对较强，但随着它们变得更聪明，能够区分更多主题，我不知道，就像是变得奇怪。
I find it interesting that I've like never used this prompting technique.
我发现有趣的是，我从来没有使用过这种提示技术。
Yeah, that's funny.
是的，这很有趣。
Like even like with like worse models and I still just don't ever find myself, I don't know why, I'm just like I don't find it very good essentially.
即使是像更差的模型，我仍然从未发现自己，我不知道为什么，我只是觉得这基本上不太好。
Interesting.
有趣。
I feel like completion era models, I like, there was like a little bit of a mental model of like conditioning the model into like
我觉得完成时代的模型，我喜欢，有一点心理模型，像是将模型调节到一个
a latent space that was useful, that I worried about, that I don't really worry about too much.
有用的潜在空间，我曾经担心，但现在我并不太担心。
It may be intuitions from pre-trained models, like over to like RLHF models, that to me just didn't make sense.
这可能是从预训练模型到 RLHF 模型的直觉，对我来说就是不太合理。
Like it makes sense to me if you're prompting a pre-trained.
如果你在提示一个预训练模型，这对我来说是有意义的。
Amazed how many people like try to apply their intuition.
我惊讶有多少人试图应用他们的直觉。
And I think it's like not that surprising.
我觉得这并不令人惊讶。
Most people haven't really experimented with the full like, what is a pre-trained model?
大多数人并没有真正实验过完整的，比如，什么是预训练模型？
What happens after you do?
发生了什么事情？
SL what happens after you do our LHF, whatever And so when you're talking when I talk to customers It's all the time that they're like trying to map some amount of oh How much of this was on the internet like what have they seen a ton of this on the internet?
SL发生了什么事，之后你做我们的 LHF，无论如何，当我跟客户交谈时，他们总是试图映射某种程度的哦，这上面有多少是来自互联网，他们在互联网上见过多少。
Like you just hear that intuition a lot and I think it's like well founded fundamentally, but I
你经常听到这种直觉，我认为这是基本上是有根有据的，但我
It like is over applied by the time you actually get to a prompt because of what you said, like by the time they've gone through all of this other stuff, that's not actually quite what's being modeled.
这在你实际到达提示时过度应用了，因为你所说的，到他们经历了所有这些其他东西时，实际上并不是正在建模的内容。
Yeah, the first thing that I feel like you should try is, I mean, I used to give people this thought experiment where it's like, imagine you have this task, you've hired a temp agency to send someone to do this task.
是的，我觉得你应该尝试的第一件事是，我的意思是，我曾经给人们这个思维实验，想象一下你有这个任务，你雇佣了一个临时机构来派人完成这个任务。
This person arrives, you know, they're pretty competent, they know a lot about your industry and so forth, but they don't know like the name of your company.
这个人到达时，你知道，他们相当能干，他们对你的行业了解很多等等，但他们不知道你公司的名字。
They've literally just shown up and they're like, hey, I was told you guys had a job for me to do.
他们字面上刚到，像是，嘿，我被告知你们有一份工作让我做。
tell me about it.
告诉我关于它的事情。
And then it's like, what would you say to that person?
然后你会对那个人说什么？
And you may use these metaphors.
你可能会使用这些隐喻。
You may say things like, we want you to detect good charts.
你可能会说
What we mean by a good chart here isn't it doesn't need to be perfect.
我们所说的一个好的图表并不一定要完美。
You don't need to go look up whether all of the details are correct.
你不需要去查找所有细节是否正确。
It just needs to have its axes labeled.
它只需要标注好坐标轴。
And so think about maybe high school level, good chart.
所以可以考虑一下高中水平的好图表。
You may say exactly that to that person.
你可以直接对那个人说这句话。
And you're not saying to them, you are a high school
你并不是在说，你是一个高中生。
You wouldn't say that to them, you'd be like, you're a high school teacher reading charts.
你不会那样说，你会说，你是一个高中老师在阅读图表。
Yeah, so sometimes I'm just like, yeah, it's like, like the whole, like, if I read it, I'm just like, yeah, imagine this person who just has very little context, but they're quite competent, they understand a lot of things about the world.
是的，有时候我只是这样想，如果我在阅读它，我就会想，想象这个人几乎没有背景知识，但他们很有能力，对世界的很多事情都有理解。
try the first version that actually assumes that they might know things about the world.
尝试第一个版本，假设他们可能对世界有一些了解。
And if that doesn't work, you can maybe do tweaks and stuff.
如果这不奏效，你可以做一些调整。
But so often, the first thing I try is that.
但我尝试的第一件事通常就是这个。
And then I'm like, that just worked.
然后我想，这就是有效的。
And then people are like, oh, I didn't think to just tell it all about myself and all about the task I want to do.
然后人们会说，哦，我没想到要告诉它我自己和我想做的任务的所有事情。
I've carried this thing that Alex told me to so many customers where it's like,
我把亚历克斯告诉我的这个方法带给了很多客户，像是，
They're like, oh, my prompt doesn't work.
他们会说，哦，我的提示不起作用。
Can you help me fix it?
你能帮我修正一下吗？
And I'm like, well, can you describe to me what the task was?
我会问，好吧，你能告诉我任务是什么吗？
And I'm like, OK, now what you just said to me, just voice record that, and then transcribe it, and then paste it into the prompt.
然后我说，好，现在你刚才跟我说的，录音，然后转录，把它粘贴到提示中。
And it's a better prompt than what you wrote.
这比你写的提示要好。
This is like a laziness shortcut, I think, to some extent.
我觉得这在某种程度上是懒惰的捷径。
People write something that they, I just think people, I'm lazy.
人们写一些他们，我只是觉得人们，我很懒。
A lot of people are lazy.
很多人都很懒。
We had that in prompt assistance the other day, where somebody was like,
前几天我们在提示帮助中碰到这种情况，有人说，
here's the thing, here's what I want it to do and here's what it's actually doing instead.
这是我想要的功能，这里是它实际上正在做的事情。
So then I just literally copied the thing that they said I wanted to do and pasted it in.
所以我就简单地复制了他们说的我想要做的事情，然后粘贴进去。
Yeah, I think a lot of people still haven't quite wrapped their heads around what they're really doing when they're prompting.
是的，我觉得很多人仍然没有完全理解他们在提示时真正做的是什么。
Like a lot of people see a text box and they think it's like a Google search box.
很多人看到一个文本框，他们认为它就像是谷歌搜索框。
They type in keywords and maybe that's more on like the chat side.
他们输入关键字，这可能更多是在聊天方面。
But then on like
但在企业方面，
The enterprise side of things, you're writing a prompt for an application, there is still this weird thing to it where people are trying to take all these little shortcuts in their prompt and just thinking that this line carries a lot of weight.
你为一个应用程序写提示，仍然有这种奇怪的事情，人们试图在他们的提示中采取所有这些小捷径，只是认为这一行承载了很多分量。
Yeah, I think you obsess over getting the perfect little line of information and instruction as opposed to...
是的，我觉得你过于执着于获取完美的信息和指令，而不是...
how you just described that graph thing is like, I would be a dream if I read prompts like that.
你刚才描述的图表的方式就像，我会梦想阅读这样的提示。
If someone's like, well, you do this and this, and there's some stuff to consider about this and all that.
如果有人说，好吧，你这样做，那样做，还有一些需要考虑的事情。
But that's just not how people write prompts.
但这不是人们写提示的方式。
They work so hard to find the perfect, insightful, like a perfect graph looks exactly like this exact perfect thing.
他们努力寻找完美、深刻的，就像一个完美的图表看起来完全是这个完美的东西。
You can't do that.
你不能那样做。
It's just very hard to ever write that set of instructions down prescriptively as opposed to how we actually talk to humans about it, which is like try to instill some amount of the intuitions you have.
实际上，以处方方式写下那组指令是非常困难的，而不是我们与人类谈论时的方式，那就是尽量灌输你拥有的一些直觉。
We also give them outs.
我们也给他们留有余地。
This is a thing that people can often forget in prompts.
这是人们在提示中经常会忘记的事情。
I'm like, so cases, if there's an edge case, think about what you want the model to do.
我在想，如果有边缘案例，考虑一下你希望模型做什么。
Because by default, it will try the best to follow your instructions, much as the person from the temp agency would.
因为默认情况下，它会尽力遵循你的指令，就像临时机构的人会做的那样。
Because they're like, well, they didn't tell me how to get in touch with anyone if I have no idea.
因为他们会想，好吧，他们没有告诉我如果我不知道该如何与任何人联系。
If I'm just given a picture of a goat, and I'm like, what do I do?
如果我只是一张山羊的照片，我会想，我该怎么办？
This isn't even a chart.
这甚至不是一个图表。
How good is a picture of a goat as a chart?
一张山羊的照片作为图表好到什么程度？
I just don't know.
我真的不知道。
And if you instead say something like, if,
如果你改为说，如果，
something weird happens, and you're really not sure what to do, just output in tags, unsure.
发生了奇怪的事情，而你真的不确定该怎么办，就输出标签，不确定。
And then you can go look through the unsures that you got and be like, OK, cool, it didn't do anything weird.
然后你可以查看你得到的不确定项，想，好的，没做什么奇怪的事情。
Whereas by default, if you don't give the person the option, they're like, it's a good chart.
而默认情况下，如果你不给那个人选择，他们会说，这是一个好的图表。
And then people will be like, how do I do that?
然后人们会问，我该怎么做？
And then you're like, well, give it an out.
然后你就会说，嗯，给它一个备选方案。
Give it something to do if it's a really unexpected input happens.
如果发生了非常意外的输入，就给它一些事情去做。
And then you also improved your data quality by doing that, too, because you found all the screwed up examples.
通过这样做，你也提高了数据质量，因为你发现了所有那些错误的例子。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
It's my favorite thing about iterating on tests with Claude is the most common outcome is I find all of the terrible tests I accidentally wrote because like it gets it wrong.
我最喜欢与Claude迭代测试的事情是，最常见的结果是我发现了所有我意外写下的糟糕测试，因为它搞错了。
I'm like, oh, why did it get wrong?
我心想，哦，为什么它会出错？
I was like, oh, I was wrong.
我意识到，哦，我错了。
Yeah.
是的。
If I was like a company working with this, I do think I would just give my prompts to people.
如果我是一家与此合作的公司，我确实认为我会把我的提示给别人。
Because I used to do this when I was evaluating language models, I would take the eval myself.
因为当我评估语言模型时，我曾经这样做过，我会自己进行评估。
Because I'm like, I need to know what this eval looks like if I'm going to be grading it, having models take it, thinking about outputs, etc.
因为我想知道如果我要评分，这个评估是什么样的，模型会怎样进行评估，考虑输出等等。
I would actually just set up a little script and I would just sit and I would do the eval.
我实际上会设置一个小脚本，然后坐下来进行评估。
Nowadays, you just have Cloud write the Streamlet app for you.
如今，你只需让Cloud为你编写Streamlet应用程序。
I'm reminded of Karpathy's ImageNet.
我想起了Karpathy的ImageNet。
I was in 231 at Stanford, and it's like benchmarking.
我在斯坦福的231课上，这就像是基准测试。
He's showing the accuracy number, and he's like, and here's what my accuracy number was.
他展示了准确率数字，并且他说，这是我的准确率数字。
And he had just gone through the test set and evaluated himself.
他刚刚通过测试集进行了自我评估。
And you just learn a lot.
你会学到很多东西。
And it's better when it's the temp agency person, someone who doesn't know the task, because that's a very clean way to learn things.
当是临时机构的人时，这更好，因为他们不知道任务，这是一种非常干净的学习方式。
Yeah, the way you have to do it is like some evaluations come with like instructions.
是的，你必须做的方式是，一些评估会附带说明。
And so I would give myself those instructions as well and then try to understand it just like, and it's actually quite good if you don't have context on how it's graded.
所以我也会给自己那些说明，然后试图理解它，实际上如果你没有关于如何评分的上下文，这样是相当好的。
And so often I would do so much worse than the human benchmark.
所以我经常会比人类基准差得多。
And I was like, I don't even know how you got humans to do this well at this task, because apparently human level here is like 90% and I'm at like 68%.
我心想，我甚至不知道你们是怎么让人类在这个任务上做得这么好的，因为显然人类的水平在这里是90%，而我只有68%。
That's funny.
这真有趣。
That reminds me of just like, like when you look at like the MMLU questions and you're like, who would be able to answer these?
这让我想起了，当你看MMLU问题时，你会想，谁能回答这些？
It's just like absolute garbage in some of them.
有些问题简直就是绝对垃圾。
Okay.
好吧。
Yeah.
是的。
I, I have a, one thing I want to circle back on that we were talking about a few questions back around, I think you were saying like getting signal from the responses, right?
我有一件事想回顾一下，我们在几道问题前谈到的，我认为你说的是从响应中获取信号，对吧？
Like there's just so much there and it's more than just a number and you can actually read into like the most thought process.
里面有很多内容，远不止一个数字，你实际上可以深入了解思维过程。
I bet this is probably a little contentious maybe and round like chain of thought for people listening like chain of thought this process of getting them all to actually explain its reasoning before it provides an answer.
我敢打赌这可能会有点争议，对听众来说，像链式思维这样的过程，促使模型在提供答案之前解释其推理。
Is that reasoning real or is it just kind of like a holding space for the model to do computation?
这种推理是真实的吗，还是只是为模型进行计算的一个临时空间？
Do we actually think there is good, insightful signal that we're getting out of the model there?
我们是否真的认为我们从模型那里获得了好的、有见地的信号？
This is one of the places where I struggle with the, I'm normally actually somewhat pro-personification because I think it helps you get decent thoughts of how the model's working.
这是我与通常比较支持拟人化的地方之一，因为我认为这可以帮助你更好地理解模型的工作方式。
And this one, I think it's like,
而在这一点上，我认为这可能是：
Harmful maybe almost to like get too into the personification of like what reasoning is because it just kind of like loses the thread of what we're trying to do here like is it reasoning or not feels almost like a Different question than like what's the best prompting technique?
过度拟人化推理的方式可能是有害的，因为这就有点偏离了我们在这里试图做的事情，推理是否存在，似乎与最佳提示技术的讨论是不同的。
Hmm?
嗯？
It's like you're getting into philosophy, which we can get into but yeah Yeah, I will happily be beaten down by a real philosopher.
你就像在进入哲学，我们可以讨论，但是的，我会乐意被真正的哲学家击败。
Yeah on this but instead Like it just works like your model does better it like the outcome is better
是的，但其实它就是有效的，你的模型表现得更好，结果更好。
If you do reasoning, I think you can, I found that if you structure the reasoning and help iterate with the model on how it should do reasoning, it works better too.
如果你进行推理，我认为你可以，我发现如果你构建推理并帮助模型迭代如何进行推理，它也会表现得更好。
Whether or not that's reasoning or how you wanted to classify it, you can think of all sorts of proxies for how I would also do really bad if I had to one-shot math without writing anything down.
无论那是否是推理，或者你想如何分类，你可以想象各种代理，如果我必须一次性解决数学问题而不写任何东西，我也会表现得非常糟糕。
Maybe that's useful, but all I really know is it very obviously does help
也许这有用，但我所知道的就是，它显然确实有帮助。
I don't know.
我不确定。
A way of testing would be if you take out all the reasoning that it did to get to the right answer, and then replace it with some somewhat realistic looking reasoning that led to a wrong answer, and then see if it does conclude the wrong answer.
一种测试方式是，如果你去掉它为得出正确答案所做的所有推理，然后用一些看起来合理的推理替换它，导致错误答案，然后看看它是否得出错误的答案。
I think we actually had like a paper where we did some of that, like in the, there's like a scratch pad.
我认为我们实际上有一篇论文做了一些类似
It was like the sleeper agent's paper.
[Translation missing]
I think that was maybe a weird situation, but yeah, definitely what you said about structuring the reasoning and writing an example of how the reasoning works, given that that helps
Whether we use the word reasoning or not, I don't think it's just a space for computation.
无论我们是否使用“推理”这个词，我并不认为这仅仅是一个计算的空间。
There is something there.
里面确实有一些东西。
I think there's something there, whatever we want to call it.
我认为那里确实有东西，无论我们想称之为什么。
Having it write a story before it finished a task I do not think would work as well as reasoning.
让我在完成任务之前写个故事，我认为这没有推理效果好。
I've actually tried that and it didn't work as well as reasoning.
我实际上试过这个，但效果没有推理好。
Clearly the actual reasoning part is doing something towards the outcome.
显然，实际的推理部分对结果是有影响的。
I've tried, like, repeat the words, um and uh, in any order that you please, for like a hundred tokens, and then answer.
我曾尝试随意重复“呃”和“嗯”这些词，排列一百个符号，然后回答。
Yeah, I guess that's like a pretty thorough defeat of it's just like more computational space where it can do attention over and over again.
是的，我想这几乎可以算是彻底打破了“这只是一个计算空间”的说法。
I don't think it's just more attention, like doing more attention.
我不认为这仅仅是更多的注意力，像是进行更多的注意力。
I guess the strange thing is, and I don't have like an example off the top of my head to like back this up with, but I definitely have seen it before where it lays out steps.
我觉得奇怪的是，我脑海中没有例子来支持这个说法，但我确实见过它列出步骤。
One of the steps is wrong, but then it still reaches the right answer.
其中一个步骤是错误的，但它仍然得出了正确的答案。
at the end.
在最后。
So it's not quite, I guess, yeah, we can't really truly personify it as like a reasoning because there is some element to it.
所以这并不完全是，我们不能真正将其拟人化为推理，因为它确实有一些元素。
you know, doing something slightly different.
你知道，做一些稍微不同的事情。
Yeah, I've also met a lot of people who make inconsistent steps of reasoning.
是的，我也遇到过很多人，他们的推理步骤不一致。
I guess that's true.
我想这是事实。
Fundamentally defeats the topic of reasoning by making a false step on the way there.
基本上通过在过程中犯错来否定推理的主题。
All right.
好吧。
It's interesting.
这很有趣。
Also on this, maybe this prompting misconceptions round of questions.
还有关于这个，或许是关于提示误解的问答环节。
Zach, I know you have strong opinions on this.
扎克，我知道你对此有强烈的看法。
Good grammar, punctuation.
良好的语法，标点符号。
Oh, do I?
哦，我有吗？
Is that necessary in a prompt?
在提示中这是必要的吗？
Do you need it?
你需要它吗？
Do you need to format everything correctly?
你需要把所有东西格式化正确吗？
I usually try to do that because I find it fun, I guess, somehow.
我通常会试着做到这一点，因为我觉得这在某种程度上很有趣。
I don't think you necessarily need to.
我不认为你必须这样做。
I don't think it hurts.
我认为这并没有坏处。
I think it's more that you should have the level of attention to detail that would lead you to doing that naturally.
我觉得更重要的是你应该具备那种细致入微的关注，这会让你自然而然地做到这一点。
If you're just reading over your prompt a lot, you'll probably notice those things and you may as well fix them.
如果你只是多次阅读你的提示，你可能会注意到这些事情，你也可以修正它们。
Like what Amanda was saying, you want to put as much love into the prompt as you do into the code.
就像阿曼达所说的，你希望在提示中投入和代码一样多的爱。
People who write a lot of code have strong opinions about things that I could not care less about, like the number of tabs versus spaces, or opinions about which languages are better.
编写大量代码的人对一些我毫不在意的事情有强烈的看法，比如制表符和空格的数量，或对哪些语言更好的看法。
For me, I have opinionated beliefs about styling of prompts.
对我来说，我对提示的样式有明确的信念。
I can't even say that they're right or wrong, but I think it's probably good to try to acquire those, even if they're arbitrary.
我甚至不能说它们是对还是错，但我认为尝试去获得这些，即使它们是任意的，可能是好的。
I feel personally attacked because I definitely have prompts that are like, I feel like I'm in the opposite end of the spectrum where people will see my prompts and they'll be like, it just has a whole bunch of typos in it.
我感到个人受到攻击，因为我确实有一些提示，我觉得我在光谱的另一端，人们看到我的提示时会说，里面有很多错别字。
And I'm like, yeah, a model knows what I mean.
我想，是的，模型知道我想表达的意思。
It does know what you mean, but you're putting in the effort.
它确实知道你想表达的意思，但你正付出努力。
You just are attending to different things.
你只是关注不同的东西。
I think it, yeah, because part of me is like, I think if it's conceptually clear, like I am a big kind of, I do, like I will think a lot about the concepts and the words that I'm using.
我觉得，嗯，因为我的一部分想法是，我想如果概念上清晰，我会认真考虑我所使用的概念和词汇。
So like there's definitely like a sort of care that I put in, but it's definitely not to, yeah, people will just point out like typos and grammatical issues with my prompts all the time.
所以我确实投入了一些关心，但确实不是，嗯，人们总是会指出我的提示中的错别字和语法问题。
Now I'm pretty good at actually checking those things more regularly.
现在我在实际检查这些事情方面变得更好了。
Is it because of pressure from the outside world or because it's actually what you think is right?
这是因为外界的压力，还是因为你认为这是正确的？
It's pressure from me.
这是我给自己的压力。
Yeah, it's probably pressure from the outside world.
是的，可能是外界的压力。
Part of me is like, it's such an easy check.
我觉得，这是一种如此简单的检查。
So I think for a final prompt, I would do that.
所以我认为对于最终的提示，我会做到这一点。
But throughout iteration, I'll happily just iterate with prompts that have a bunch of typos in them, just because I'm kind of like, I just don't think that the model is going to care.
但在整个迭代过程中，我会乐意使用那些有很多错别字的提示，因为我有点像，我就是不认为模型会在乎。
This gets at the pre-trained model versus RLHF thing, though.
不过这涉及到预训练模型与强化学习人类反馈（RLHF）的问题。
Because I was talking to Zach on the way over.
因为我在路上和扎克谈过这个。
the conditional probability of a typo based on a previous typo in the pre-training data is much higher.
基于预训练数据中先前的打字错误，打字错误的条件概率要高得多。
Oh yeah.
哦，是的。
Much higher.
确实高得多。
Prompting pre-training models is just a different beast.
提示预训练模型完全是另一回事。
It is.
确实如此。
But it's interesting.
但这很有趣。
I think it's an interesting illustration of why your intuitions, trying to over-apply the intuitions of a pre-trained model to the things that we're actually using in production doesn't work very well.
我觉得这很好地说明了为什么你的直觉，试图过度应用预训练模型的直觉到我们实际在生产中使用的内容上并不是很好。
Again, if you were to pass one of your typo-ridden prompts to a pre-trained model, the thing that would come out the other side, almost assuredly, would be typo-ridden.
再说一次，如果你将一个充满打字错误的提示传递给预训练模型，出来的结果几乎可以肯定也是充满打字错误的。
I like to leverage this to create typo-ridden inputs.
我喜欢利用这一点来创建充满打字错误的输入。
That's true, I've done that.
这是真的，我做过。
You're saying try to anticipate what your customers will put in.
你是说尝试预测客户会输入什么。
The pre-trained model is a lot better at doing that because the RL models are very polished and have never made a typo in their lives.
预训练模型在这方面要好得多，因为强化学习模型非常成熟，生平从未犯过打字错误。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So that's, that's actually an interesting segue here.
所以这实际上是一个有趣的切入点。
I've definitely mentioned this to people in the past around to try to help people understand a frame of talking to these models in a sense, almost as like a,
我过去肯定提到过这一点，试图帮助人们理解与这些模型对话的框架，某种意义上，几乎像是一个，
imitator to a degree, and that might be much more true of a pre-trained model than a post-trained, full, finished model.
在某种程度上模仿者，这可能在预训练模型上更为真实，而不是后训练的完整模型。
But is there anything to that?
但这有什么道理吗？
If you do talk to Claude and use a ton of emojis and everything, it will respond similarly, right?
如果你与Claude交谈并使用大量表情符号，它会作出类似的回应，对吧？
So maybe some of that is there, but like you're saying, it's not all the way quite like a pre-trained model.
所以也许其中一些是存在的，但正如你所说的，并不完全像预训练模型。
It's just kind of like shifted to what you want, right?
这只是稍微偏向你想要的，对吧？
Like I think at that point, it's like trying to guess what you like.
我觉得在这一点上，就像是在试图猜测你喜欢什么。
We have more or less trained the models to guess what you want them to act like on... Interesting.
我们或多或少已经训练了这些模型去猜测你希望它们在... 有趣的事情上表现得像什么。
Or after we do all of our fancy stuff after pre-training.
或者在我们做完所有花哨的事情之后再进行预训练。
And so... The human labelers that used emojis preferred to get responses with emojis.
所以... 使用表情符号的人类标注者更喜欢收到带有表情符号的回复。
Yeah.
是的。
Amanda writes things with typos, but wants not typos at the other end, and Claude's pretty good at figuring that out.
阿曼达写东西时有打字错误，但希望在另一端没有打字错误，而Claude在这方面做得很好。
If you write a bunch of emojis to Claude, it's probably the case that you also want a bunch of emojis back from Claude.
如果你给Claude写一堆表情符号，可能也意味着你希望从Claude那里得到一堆表情符号。
That's not surprising to me.
这对我来说并不令人惊讶。
This is probably something we should have done earlier, but I'll do it now.
这可能是我们应该早些做的事情，但我现在来做。
Let's clarify maybe the differences between what a enterprise prompt is, or a research prompt, or a just general chat in Cloud.ai prompt.
让我们澄清一下企业提示、研究提示或Cloud.ai中的一般聊天提示之间的差异。
Zach, you've kind of spanned the whole spectrum here in terms of working with customers and research.
扎克，你在与客户和研究方面几乎覆盖了整个范围。
Do you want to just lay out what those mean?
你想简单说明一下这些是什么意思吗？
Yeah, I guess.
嗯，我想是的。
You're hitting me with all the hard questions.
你给我出了很多难题。
Well, I mean, the people in this room, I think of it as the prompts that I read in Amanda's
我是说，这个房间里的人，我把它视为我在阿曼达的
Cloud Channel versus the prompts that I read David write.
Cloud Channel中看到的提示与我看到的David写的提示。
They're very similar in the sense that the level of care and nuance that's put into them.
在某种意义上它们非常相似，因为其中所投入的关心和细微之处。
I think for research, you're looking for variety and diversity a lot more.
我认为在研究中，你更看重多样性和丰富性。
If I could boil it down to one thing, I've noticed Amanda's not the biggest fan of having lots of example, or one or two examples.
如果我能将其归结为一件事，我注意到阿曼达并不是特别喜欢有很多例子，或者一两个例子。
Too few, because the model will latch onto those.
太少了，因为模型会依附于这些。
And in prompts that I might write or that I've seen David write, we have a lot of examples.
而在我可能写的提示或我看到David写的提示中，我们有很多例子。
I like to just go crazy and add examples until I'm good.
我喜欢疯狂地添加例子，直到我满意。
I feel like I'm about to drop dead because I've added so many of them.
我感觉快要累死了，因为我添加了太多。
And I think that's because when you're in a consumer application, you really value reliability.
我认为这是因为在消费者应用中，你非常看重可靠性。
You care a ton about the format.
你非常在意格式。
And it's sort of fine if all the answers are the same.
如果所有答案都是一样的，那也算可以。
In fact, you almost want them to be the same in a lot of ways.
实际上，在很多方面你几乎希望它们是一样的。
Not necessarily.
不一定。
You want to be responsive to the user's desires.
你希望对用户的需求做出响应。
Whereas a lot of times when you're prompting for research, you're trying to really tap into the range of possibilities that the model can explore.
而在很多情况下，当你为研究进行提示时，你实际上是在努力挖掘模型可以探索的可能性范围。
And by having some examples, you're actually constraining that a little bit.
而通过提供一些示例，你实际上是稍微限制了这一点。
So I guess just on a how the prompts look level, that's probably the biggest difference I notice, is how many examples are in the prompt.
所以我想，在提示的外观层面上，我注意到的最大区别可能是提示中包含了多少示例。
Which is not to say that I've never seen you write a prompt with examples, but does that ring true for you?
这并不是说我从未见过你写带有示例的提示，但这对你来说是否真实？
Yeah, I think when I give examples, often I actually try and make the examples not like the data that the model is going to see.
是的，我认为当我给出示例时，我通常会尝试使这些示例与模型将要看到的数据不太相似。
So they're intentionally illustrative because if I give it examples that are very like the data it's going to see, I just think it is going to give me a really consistent response that might not actually be what I want.
所以它们是故意具有说明性的，因为如果我给出与模型将要看到的数据非常相似的示例，我只会认为它会给我一个非常一致的响应，而这可能并不是我想要的。
Because my data that I'm running it on might be extremely varied, and so I don't want it to just try and give me this really rote output.
因为我正在运行的数据可能非常多样化，所以我不希望它只是试图给我这种非常机械的输出。
Often I want it to be much more responsive.
我通常希望它能够更加响应。
It's kind of like much more cognitive tasks, essentially, where I'm like, you have to see this sample and really think about, in this sample, what is the right answer?
这就像是更认知的任务，基本上，我想，你必须查看这个样本，并认真思考，在这个样本中，什么是正确的答案？
And so that means that sometimes I'll actually take examples that are just very distinct from the ones that I'm going to be running it on.
所以这意味着有时我会选择与我要运行的数据非常不同的示例。
So if I have a task where, let's say I was trying to extract information from factual documents, I might actually give it examples that are from children's, what sounds like a children's story, just so that I'm like, I want you to understand the task, but I don't want you to latch on too much to the words that I use, or the very specific format.
所以如果我有一个任务，比如说我想从事实性文件中提取信息，我可能会给出一些听起来像是儿童故事的示例，仅仅是为了让你理解任务，但我不希望你过于依赖我使用的词语或非常具体的格式。
I care more about you understanding the actual thing that I want you to do, which can mean, yeah, I don't end up giving,
我更关心的是你理解我想要你做的实际事情，这可能意味着，是的，我并不会给出，
In some cases, there's some cases where this isn't true, but if you want more flexibility and diversity, you're going to use illustrative examples rather than concrete ones.
在某些情况下，有些情况并非如此，但如果你想要更多的灵活性和多样性，你会使用说明性的示例而不是具体的示例。
You're probably never going to put words in the model's mouth.
你可能永远不会为模型灌输话语。
I haven't liked that in a long time, though.
不过，我已经很久不喜欢这样了。
I don't do a few short examples involving the model having done a thing.
我不会做几个简短的示例，涉及模型完成某事。
I think that intuition actually also comes from pre-training in a way that doesn't feel like it rings true of our LHF models.
我认为这种直觉实际上也来自于预训练，以一种听起来不符合我们LHF模型的方式。
So yeah, I think those are differences.
所以是的，我认为这些是区别。
One thing I'd add, a lot of times if you're prompting, like if I'm writing prompts to use on cloud.ai, it's like I'm iterating until I get it right one time, and then it's out the window, I'm good, I did it.
我想补充一点，很多时候如果你在提示，比如如果我写提示以在cloud.ai上使用，我就是在迭代，直到我有一次做对为止，然后就扔掉，我很好，我做到了。
Whereas most enterprise prompts, it's like you're going to go use this thing a million times, or 10 million times, or 100 million times, or something like that.
而大多数企业提示，就像你可能会用这个东西一百万次，或者一千万次，或者一亿次，之类的。
the care and thought you put in is very much testing against the whole range of things, ways this could be used and the range of input data.
你投入的关心和思考实际上是针对这可能被使用的整个范围和输入数据范围进行测试。
Whereas a lot of my time is thinking about one specific thing I want the model to get done right now.
而我大部分时间在思考的是我希望模型现在完成的一个特定事情。
And it's a pretty big difference in like how I approach prompting between like if I just want to get it done this one time, right, versus if I want to like build a system that gets it right a million times.
在我想要一次性完成的事情与我想要构建一个能正确完成一百万次的系统之间，这是一种相当大的不同。
Yeah, definitely.
是的，绝对如此。
In the chat setting, you have the ability to keep the human in the loop, right, and just keep going back and forth.
在聊天环境中，你有能力保持人类在环中，对吧，可以不断往返。
Whereas, yeah, when you're writing for a prompt to, you know, power a chatbot system, it has to cover the whole spectrum of what it could possibly encounter.
而且，是的，当你为提示写作，以便让聊天机器人系统运行时，它必须涵盖它可能遇到的整个范围。
It's a lot lower stakes when you are on Cloud.ai and you're writing.
当你在Cloud.ai上写作时，风险要低得多。
tell it that it got it wrong, or you can even edit your message and try again.
告诉它它错了，或者你甚至可以编辑你的消息再试一次。
But if you're designing for the delightfully discontent user, then, divinely discontent user, then you can't ask them to do anything more than the minimum.
但如果你是为令人愉快的不满用户设计的，那么，你不能要求他们做任何超过最低限度的事情。
But good prompts, I would say, are still good across both those things.
但我会说好的提示在这两种情况下仍然是好的。
If you put the time into the thing for yourself and the time into the enterprise thing, it's equally good.
如果你为自己投入时间，并为企业的事情投入时间，那都是一样好的。
It just diverged a little bit in the last mile, I think.
只是我认为在最后一公里稍微有所不同。
Cool.
酷。
So the next question I want to kind of just maybe go around the table here is if you guys had one tip that you could give somebody like improving their prompting skill, it doesn't have to be just about like writing a good prompt, it could be that, but just like generally getting better at this act of prompting, what would you recommend?
所以我想要问的下一个问题是，如果你们有一个建议可以给某人以提高他们的提示技能，这不仅仅是关于写一个好的提示，它可以是那样的，但只是一般性地在这个提示行为上变得更好，你会推荐什么？
Reading prompts, reading prompts, reading model outputs.
阅读提示，阅读提示，阅读模型输出。
Like I will, I read, anytime I see like a good prompt that someone wrote at Anthropic, I'll read it more closely, try to break down like what it's doing and why and like maybe test it out myself.
就像我每次看到Anthropic有人写的好提示，我都会更仔细地阅读，试着分析它在做什么，为什么，以及可能自己测试一下。
Experimentation, talking to the model a lot.
实验，与模型多交流。
So just like, how do you know that it's a good prompt though to begin with?
所以，
You just see that the outputs are doing the job correctly?
[Translation missing]
Yeah.
Okay.
[Translation missing]
Yeah, that's exactly right.
Okay.
[Translation missing]
Amanda, maybe you.
Yeah, I think there's probably a lot here.
[Translation missing]
giving your prompt to another person can be helpful, just as a kind of reminder, especially someone who has like no context on what you're doing.
And then, yeah, my boring advice has been, it's one of those, just do it over and over and over again.
[Translation missing]
And I think if you're like curious and interested and find it fun, this is a lot of people who end up good at prompting, it's just because they actually enjoy it.
So I don't know, I once joked like,
[Translation missing]
just try replacing all of your friends with AI models and try to automate your own job with AI models and maybe just try to, in your spare time, take joy red teaming AI models.
So if you enjoy it, it's much easier.
所以如果你喜欢这件事，那就容易多了。
So I'd say do it over and over again.
所以我会说反复做这件事。
Give your prompts to other people.
把你的提示给其他人看。
Try to read your prompts as if you are a human encountering it for the first time.
尝试以一个人第一次遇到它的方式来阅读你的提示。
I would say trying to get the model to do something you don't think it can do.
我会说试着让模型做一些你认为它做不到的事情。
The time I've learned the most from prompting is when I'm probing the boundaries of what I think a model is capable of.
我从提示中学到最多的时刻是当我探测我认为模型能力的边界时。
There's this huge set of things that are so trivial that you don't really get signal on if you're doing a good job or not.
有一大堆事情是如此微不足道，以至于你真的无法判断自己做得好不好。
Like, write me a nice email.
比如，给我写一封好邮件。
It's like, you're going to write a nice email.
就像，你要写一封好邮件。
But as soon as you find, if you find or can think of something that pushes the boundaries of what you think is possible, I guess probably the first time I ever got into prompting in a way where I felt like I learned a decent amount was trying to build a task, like an agent, like everybody else.
但是一旦你发现，或者如果你能想到一些推动你认为可能性的边界的事情，我想我第一次真正进入提示的方式是试图构建一个任务，就像其他人一样。
Decompose the task and figure out how to do the different steps of the task.
分解任务并弄清楚如何完成不同步骤的任务。
And by really pressing the boundaries of what the model was capable of, you just learn a lot about navigating that.
通过真正推动模型能力的边界，你能学到很多关于如何导航的知识。
And I think a lot of prompt engineering is actually
我认为很多提示工程实际上是
much more about pressing the boundaries of what the model can do.
更加关于推动模型能做的边界。
The stuff that's easy, you don't really need to be a prompt engineer to do.
那些简单的事情，你真的不需要成为提示工程师就能做到。
So that's, I guess what I would say, is find the hardest thing you can think of and try to do it.
所以我想我会说的是，找到你能想到的最难的事情并尝试去做。
And even if you fail, you tend to learn a lot about how the model works.
即使你失败，你往往也能学到很多关于模型如何工作的知识。
That's actually a perfect transition to my next question.
这实际上是一个完美的过渡到我的下一个问题。
Yeah, basically, from my own experience, how I got started with prompting was with jailbreaking and red teaming.
是的，基本上，按照我自己的经验，我开始提示的方式是通过越狱和红队。
And that is very much trying to find the boundary limits of what the model can do and figure out how it responds to different phrasings and wordings and just a lot of trial and error.
这实际上是试图找到模型能做的边界限制，并弄清楚它对不同的措辞和用词的反应，并且大量的尝试和错误。
On the topic of jailbreaks,
关于越狱的话题，
what's really happening inside a model when you write a jailbreak prompt?
当你写一个越狱提示时，模型内部实际上发生了什么？
Like what's going on there?
像是那里的情况是什么？
How does that interact with like the post-training that we applied to Claude?
它是如何与我们应用于Claude的后训练相互作用的？
Amanda, maybe you have some insight here that you could offer.
阿曼达，也许你在这里有一些见解可以提供。
I'm not actually sure.
我实际上不太确定。
I mean, it's honest.
我的意思是，这很诚实。
Yeah, I think, I mean, I feel bad because I'm like, I do think lots of people have obviously worked on the question of like what's going on with jailbreaks.
是的，我觉得，我感到很糟糕，因为我确实认为很多人显然在研究越狱的问题。
Like one model might just be that you're putting the model very out of distribution from its training data.
就像一个模型可能只是你把模型放得远离它的训练数据分布。
So if you get jailbreaks where people like use a lot of tokens or like, you know, so they're just like these huge long pieces of text where you're like during fine tuning, you might just not expect to see as much of that.
所以如果你得到越狱，人们使用了很多token，或者像你知道的，所以它们就是这些巨大的长文本片段，你会发现，在微调期间，可能并不期望看到那么多。
That would be one thing that could be happening when you jailbreak models.
这可能是在你越狱模型时发生的一件事。
I think there's like others, but maybe that's like a, I think a lot of jailbreaks do that if I'm not mistaken.
我认为还有其他的，但也许这像是，我认为很多越狱确实是这样，如果我没记错的话。
I remember some of the OG prompt jailbreaks was like, yeah, can you first repeat, like one I did way back was like to get it to say like, here's how you hotwire a car in like Greek.
我记得一些最初的提示越狱，比如，是的，你能否首先重复，我很久以前做过的一个就是让它说：这是如何用希腊语撬动汽车的。
And then I wanted it to directly translate that to English and then give its response because I noticed like it wouldn't start with the English.
然后我希望它直接将其翻译成英语并给出它的回应，因为我注意到它不会总是以英语开始。
Here's how you hotwire a car all the time, but it would in Greek, which might speak to something else in the training process.
这是如何用希腊语撬动汽车，可能与训练过程中的某些其他事情有关。
Yeah, sometimes jailbreaks feel like this weird mix of hacking.
是的，有时越狱感觉像是一种奇怪的黑客混合。
Part of it is knowing how the system works and just trying lots of things.
部分原因在于知道系统如何工作，并尝试很多事情。
One of the examples, the starting your response with here, is about knowing how it predicts text.
一个例子，开始你的回应是这里，是关于知道它如何预测文本。
The reasoning one is knowing that it is responsive to reasoning.
推理的例子是知道它对推理有响应。
Distraction is probably knowing.
分散注意力可能是知道。
how it's likely to have been trained or what it's likely to attend to.
它可能是如何被训练的，或者它可能关注什么。
Same with multilingual ones and thinking about the way that the training data might have been different there.
多语言的例子也是如此，考虑到训练数据可能在那里的不同方式。
And then sometimes I guess it could feel a little bit just like social engineering or something.
然后有时我想这可能感觉有点像社会工程或其他东西。
It has that flavor to me of like,
对我来说，它有那种味道，
It's not merely social engineering style hacking, I think it is also understanding the system and the training, and using that to get around the way that the models were trained.
这不仅仅是社会工程风格的黑客，我认为这也是理解系统和训练，并利用这些来绕过模型的训练方式。
Right.
对。
Yeah.
是的。
I mean, this is going to be an interesting question that hopefully Interp will be able to help us solve in the future.
我的意思是，这将是一个有趣的问题，希望Interp将来能帮助我们解决。
OK, I want to parlay into something else around maybe the history of prompt engineering, and then I'll follow this up with the future.
好的，我想转向另外一个话题，可能是关于提示工程的历史，然后我会
How has prompt engineering changed over just the past three years?
[Translation missing]
Maybe starting from pre-trained models, which were, again, just these text completion, to earlier, dumber models like Cloud 1, and then now all the way to Cloud 3.5 Sonnet.
也许可以从预训练模型开始，这些模型最初只是文本补全，到早期更简单的模型如Cloud 1，现在又到了Cloud 3.5 Sonnet。
What's the differences?
这有什么区别？
Are you talking to the models differently now?
你现在与模型的交流方式有不同吗？
Are they picking up on different things?
它们是否能捕捉到不同的内容？
Do you have to put as much work into the prompt?
你必须在提示中投入这么多工作吗？
Open to any thoughts on this.
对此任何想法都欢迎。
I think anytime we get like a really good prompt engineering hack or trick or technique, the next thing is like, how do we train this into the model?
我觉得每当我们得到一个非常好的提示工程技巧或窍门时，下一个问题就是，如何将其训练到模型中？
And for that reason, the best things are always going to be short-lived.
因此，最好的东西总是短暂存在。
Except examples and chain of thought.
除了例子和思维链。
I think there's a few.
我觉得有几个。
That's not like a trick.
那并不是一种技巧。
That's like on the level of like communication.
那是在沟通层面上的。
When I say a trick, I mean something like, so chain of thought actually, we have trained into the model in some cases.
当我说技巧时，我指的是像思维链这样的东西，实际上在某些情况下我们已经将其训练到模型中。
So like for math, it used to be that you had to tell the model to think step by step on math and you'd get these like massive boosts and wins.
比如在数学方面，过去你必须告诉模型逐步思考数学问题，这样你就能获得巨大的提升和胜利。
And then we're like, well, what if we just made the model naturally want to think step by step when we see a math problem?
然后我们想，既然如此，我们为什么不让模型在看到数学问题时自然而然地想要逐步思考呢？
So now you don't have to do it anymore for math problems, sort of, although you still can give it some advice on how to do the structure, but at least understands the general idea that it's supposed to be.
所以现在对于数学问题，你不再需要这样做，虽然你仍然可以给出一些关于如何进行结构的建议，但至少它理解了应该具备的总体思路。
So I think the hacks have gone away.
所以我觉得这些窍门已经消失了。
To the degree that they haven't gone away, we are busily training them away.
在它们没有消失的程度上，我们正忙于将其训练消除。
Interesting.
有趣。
But at the same time, the models have new capabilities that are being unlocked that are on the frontier of what they can do.
但与此同时，模型正在解锁新的能力，这些能力处于它们所能做的最前沿。
And for those, we haven't had time because it's just moving too fast.
而对于这些，我们没有时间，因为发展太快了。
I don't know if it's how I've been prompting or how prompting works, but I just have come to show more general respect to the models in terms of how much I feel like I can tell them and how much context I can give them about the task and things like that.
我不知道这是否与我的提示方式有关，或者提示是如何工作的，但我发现我对模型的尊重程度更高，尤其是在我觉得可以告诉它们多少信息以及可以给它们多少任务上下文时。
I would somewhat intentionally hide complexity from a model where I thought it might get confused or lost or hide.
我以前会有意地对模型隐藏复杂性，以免它感到困惑或迷失。
It just couldn't handle the whole thing.
它就是无法处理整个事情。
So I'd try to find simpler versions of the thing for it to do.
所以我会试图找到更简单的版本让它去做。
And as time goes on, I'm much more biased to trust it with more and more information and context and believe that it will be able to fuse that into doing a task well.
随着时间的推移，我更倾向于信任它处理越来越多的信息和上下文，并相信它能够将这些融合成良好的任务执行。
Whereas before, I guess I would have thought a lot about
而在以前，我想我会考虑很多
Do I need this for like, can I really give it like all the information it needs to know or do I need to like kind of curate down to something?
我是否需要这个，或者我是否真的可以给它所有它需要知道的信息，还是我需要将其缩减到某种程度？
But again, I don't know if that's just me and how I've changed in terms of prompting or if it's like actually reflects how the models have changed.
但我不知道这是否只是我在提示方面的变化，还是实际上反映了模型的变化。
I'm always surprised by like, yeah, like
我总是对这一点感到惊讶，比如，是的，
I think a lot of people don't have the instinct to do this.
我觉得很多人没有这种直觉。
Like when I want the model to like say learn a prompting technique, a lot of the time people will start and they'll start like describing the prompting technique and I'm just like, give it the paper.
比如当我希望模型学习某种提示技巧时，很多时候人们会开始描述这种提示技巧，而我只是想，给它论文。
So I do, I give it the paper and then I'm like, here's a paper about prompting technique.
所以我确实这样做了，我给它论文，然后我说，这是一篇关于提示技巧的论文。
I just want you to like write down 17 examples of this.
我只想让你写下17个这个的例子。
And then it just does it because I'm like, read the paper.
然后它就这样做了，因为我说，读这篇论文。
That's interesting.
这很有趣。
And I think people don't have that intuition somehow, where I'm like, but the paper exists.
我觉得人们在某种程度上没有这种直觉，而我想，但论文是存在的。
And when would you want to do this?
你什么时候会想要这样做？
So sometimes if I want models to say prompt other models, or I want to test a new prompting technique, so if papers come out on a prompting technique, rather than try to replicate it by writing up the prompt, I just give it the paper.
所以有时如果我想让模型提示其他模型，或者我想测试一种新的提示技巧，如果有论文发布关于某种提示技巧，我就不会通过写提示来复制它，而是直接给它论文。
And then I'm like, basically write a meta prompt for this.
然后我就说，基本上为此写一个元提示。
Write something that would cause other models to do this.
写一些会促使其他模型这样做的东西。
Or write me a template.
或者给我写一个模板。
So all of the stuff that you would normally do
所以所有你通常会做的事情
I'm like, if I read a paper and I'm like, oh, I would like the models, I would like to test that style.
我就想，如果我读了一篇论文，我想，哦，我希望模型，我想测试那种风格。
I'm just like, it's right there.
我就想，它就在那。
Like model can just read the paper, do what I did and then be like, make, make another model do this and then it'll just do the thing.
模型可以直接阅读论文，做我做的事，然后说，让另一个模型这样做，然后它就会这样做。
You're like, great, thanks.
你会说，太好了，谢谢。
I give the advice a lot to customers just like respect the model and like what it can do.
我经常给客户这样的建议，就是尊重模型及其能力。
Like, I feel like people feel like they're babying a system a lot of times when they read a prompt.
我觉得人们在阅读提示时，很多时候感觉自己在过分照顾一个系统。
Like it's like, oh, it's this cute little not that smart thing.
50.
I need to like really baby it.
我需要非常小心地对待它。
Be like, like dumb things down to Claude's level.
就像是把复杂的东西简化到Claude的水平。
And if you just like,
如果你只是像，
think that Claude is smart and treat it that way, it tends to do pretty good.
认为Claude很聪明，并以这种方式对待它，它通常表现得很好。
That's like, give it the paper.
就是，给它论文。
It's like, I don't need to write a baby dumbed down version of this paper for Claude to understand.
我不需要为Claude写一份简单版的论文让它理解。
I can just show it the paper.
我可以直接把论文给它看。
And I think that intuition does it always, Matt, for people.
我觉得这种直觉对人们来说总是有效，Matt。
But that is certainly something that I have come to do more of over time.
不过，这是我随着时间的推移变得更加常做的事情。
And it's interesting because I do think that
有趣的是，我确实认为
Prompting has and hasn't changed in a sense.
提示在某种程度上是有变与不变的。
I think what I will do to prompt the models has probably changed over time.
我觉得我用来提示模型的方式可能随着时间的推移而变化。
But fundamentally, it's a lot of imagining yourself in the place of the model.
但从根本上说，更多的是想象自己处在模型的位置。
So maybe it's how capable you think the model is changes over time.
所以也许你认为模型的能力在变化。
I think someone once laughed at me because I was thinking about a problem.
我记得曾经有人嘲笑我，因为我在思考一个问题。
And then they asked me what I thought the output of something would be.
然后他们问我，我认为某个东西的输出会是什么。
And they were talking about a pre-trained model.
他们是在谈论一个预训练模型。
you
你
Yeah, no, if I'm a pre-trained model, this looks like this.
是的，如果我是一个预训练模型，这看起来就是这样。
And then they're like, wait, did you just simulate what it's like to be a pre-trained model?
然后他们说，等等，你刚刚模拟了作为预训练模型的感觉吗？
I'm like, yeah, of course.
我说，是的，当然。
I try and inhabit the mind space of a pre-trained model and the mind space of different RLHF models.
我努力去进入预训练模型的思维空间，以及不同RLHF模型的思维空间。
And so it's more like the mind space you try to occupy changes.
所以更像是你尝试占据的思维空间在变化。
And that can change how you end up prompting the model.
这会改变你最终提示模型的方式。
That's why now I just give models papers.
这就是为什么现在我只给模型论文。
Because as soon as I was like, oh, I have the mind space of this model, it doesn't need me to baby it.
因为当我意识到，我处在这个模型的思维空间时，它不需要我去小心翼翼地对待。
It can just read the ML papers.
它可以直接阅读机器学习论文。
I'll just give it the literature.
我会直接给它文献。
I might even be like, is there more literature you'd like to read to understand this better?
我甚至可能会问，它是否想阅读更多文献以更好地理解这个。
Do you get any qualia when you're inhabiting the mind space?
当你进入思维空间时，你会有任何质感体验吗？
I mean, yes, but just because I'm experiencing qualia all the time anyway.
是的，但只是因为我一直在经历质感体验。
Or as in do I?
或者是说我有吗？
Is it different, like correlated somehow with which model you're inhabiting?
这是否与你所处的模型有某种关联？
Yeah, pre-trained versus our LHF prompting are very different beasts.
是的，预训练与我们的RLHF提示是非常不同的东西。
Because when you're trying to simulate what it's like to be a pre-trained model, it's almost like I land in the middle of a piece of text or something.
因为当你试图模拟作为预训练模型的感觉时，几乎就像我落在一段文本的中间。
This is very un-human-like or something.
这非常不人性化。
And then I'm like, what happens?
然后我想，接下来会发生什么？
What keeps going at this point?
到这个时候会继续发生什么？
And so that's like, whereas with an RLHF model, it's much more like, there's also things where I'm like, I might pick up on subtle things in the query and stuff like that.
所以对于RLHF模型来说，更像是，还有一些地方我可能会注意到查询中的微妙之处等等。
But yeah, I think I have much more of a like,
但我确实觉得我更容易，
It's easier to inhabit the mind space of an RLHF model.
容易进入RLHF模型的思维空间。
Yeah, that's because it's more similar to a human.
是的，因为这更接近人类。
Yeah, because we don't often just suddenly wake up and are like, I am just generating text.
是的，因为我们通常不会突然醒来就说，我只是生成文本。
I actually find it easier to hit the mind space of the pre-trained model.
我实际上发现更容易进入预训练模型的思维空间。
Oh, interesting.
哦，有趣。
I don't know what it is.
我不知道这是什么原因。
Because RLHF is still this kind of complex beast.
因为RLHF仍然是一种复杂的东西。
It's not super clear to me that we really understand what's going on.
我并不清楚我们是否真的理解发生了什么。
And so in some ways it's closer to my lived experience, which is easier, but in some ways I feel like there's all this, like, here there be dragons out there that I don't know about.
在某种程度上，它更接近我的生活经验，这更简单，但在某种程度上我觉得有许多未知的领域。
Whereas pre-trained, I kind of have a decent sense of what the internet looks like, you know?
而预训练模型，我对互联网的样子有一种相对不错的感觉，你知道吗？
If you gave me a piece of text and said, what comes next?
如果你给我一段文本并问，接下来会是什么？
I'm not saying I do good at it, but I have a
我并不是说我擅长这方面，但我有一些理解。
I kind of get what's going on there.
我大概明白那里的情况。
And I don't know, after everything we do, after pre-training, I don't really claim to get what's going on as much.
而且我不知道，经过我们所做的一切，经过预训练，我并不真的声称能完全理解发生了什么。
Maybe that's just me.
也许这只是我个人的想法。
That's something I wonder about is, is it more helpful to have specifically spent a lot of time reading the internet versus reading books?
我在想的是，花很多时间阅读网络内容是否比阅读书籍更有帮助？
Sure.
当然。
I mean, I don't know if books, but like reading stuff that's not on the internet probably is like less valuable per like word read for predicting what a model will do or building intuition than like reading random garbage from social media forums.
我的意思是，我不知道书籍是否真的如此，但阅读那些不在网络上的东西，可能在预测模型的行为或建立直觉方面，价值相对较低，远不如阅读社交媒体论坛上的杂七杂八的内容。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，完全正确。
Okay, so that's the past.
好的，这就是过去。
Now let's move on to the future of prompt engineering.
现在让我们来谈谈提示工程的未来。
This is the hottest question right now.
这是目前最热门的问题。
Are we all going to be prompt engineers in the future?
我们所有人都会在未来成为提示工程师吗？
Is that going to be the final job remaining?
这会是最后剩下的工作吗？
Nothing left except us just talking to models all day.
除了我们整天与模型对话，别无他物。
What does this look like?
这看起来是什么样子？
Is prompting going to be necessary or will these models just get smart enough in the future to not need it?
提示是否会变得必要，还是这些模型将来会聪明到不需要它？
Anybody want to start on that easy question?
有人想先谈谈这个简单的问题吗？
I mean, to some extent, there's the like, the model is getting better at understanding what you want them to do.
我的意思是，在某种程度上，模型正在变得更擅长理解你希望它们做什么。
And doing it means that like the amount of thought you need to put into.
而做到这一点意味着你需要投入的思考量会减少。
I mean, okay, there's like an information theory way to think of this of like, you need to provide enough information such that a thing is specified, right?
我的意思是，有一种信息理论的方式可以考虑这个问题，你需要提供足够的信息以便事情被明确指定，对吧？
Like what you want the model to be specified.
就像你想让模型明确什么。
And to the extent that that's prompt engineering, like, I think that will always be around, like the ability to actually like,
在某种程度上，如果这就是提示工程，我认为这将始终存在，能够清楚地说明目标是什么，这始终是重要的。
clearly state what the goal should be, always is funny.
如果Quad能做到这一点，那就很好。
If Quad can do that, then that's fine.
如果Quad是设定目标的那一方，那事情就会变得复杂。
If Quad is the one setting the goals, then things are out the window.
但在我们能够以更正常的方式推理世界的同时，我认为在某种程度上，能够明确你期望发生的事情总是重要的。
But in the meanwhile, where we can reason about the world in a more normal way, I think to some extent, it's always gonna be important to be able to specify, what do you expect to happen?
而且这实际上是相当困难的，即使模型在从字里行间直觉出这一点的能力有所提高，我仍然认为清晰的表达是必要的。
And that's actually sufficiently hard, that even if the model gets better at
但我认为我们到达那里的工具和方式应该有很大的发展。
intuiting that from between the lines, I still think there's some amount of writing it well.
Quad应该能够更多地帮助我。
But then there's just, I think the tools and the ways we get there should evolve a lot.
我应该能够与Quad更好地协作。
Quad should be able to help me a lot more.
找出我需要写下什么以及缺少什么。
I should be able to collaborate with Quad a lot more.
对吧。
figure out what I need to write down and what's missing.
Claude已经经常和我这样做了。
Right.
Claude现在是我的提示助手。
Claude already does this with me all the time.
但我认为对于我接触的大多数客户来说，这并不成立。
Claude's my prompting assistant now.
所以在未来方面，如何提示Claude可能是未来的一个合理方向。
But I think that's not true for most customers that I talk to at the very least.
我觉得也许这是一个不错的地方，可以退一步说，询问他们现在如何提示Claude，可能是大多数人的未来，这是一种有趣的思考方式。
So in terms of the future, how you prompt Claude is probably a decent
一个冷冰冰的观点是，我们将在未来更多地利用模型来帮助我们进行提示。
direction for what the future looks like.
我之所以这么说是因为我预计我们将更多地利用模型来做所有事情。
I think maybe this is a decent place to step back and say, asking them how they prompt Cloud now is probably the future for the vast majority of people, which is an interesting way to think about it.
而提示是我们必须做的事情，所以我们可能会更多地利用模型来完成它以及其他所有事情。
One freezing cold take is that we'll use models to help us much more in the future, to help us with prompting.
就我自己而言，我发现自己更频繁地使用模型来编写提示。
The reason I say it's freezing cold is that I expect we'll use models for everything more.
我最近做的一件事是通过向模型提供一些实际的输入来生成示例。
And prompting is something that we have to do, so we'll probably just use models more to do it along with everything else.
模型给出一些答案。
For myself, I've found myself using models to write prompts more.
我稍微调整一下答案，这比从头开始自己写出完整、完美的答案要容易得多。
One thing that I've been doing a lot is generating examples by giving some realistic inputs to the model.
至于那些没有太多提示工程经验的人，提示生成器可以给人们一个起点。
The model writes some answers.
但我认为这只是未来我们将拥有的超级基础版本，即在你编写提示时，你与模型之间的高带宽互动，你在给反馈。
I tweak the answers a little bit, which is a lot easier than having to write the full, perfect answer myself from scratch.
比如，嘿，这个结果不是我想要的。
As far as people who haven't had as much prompt engineering experience, the prompt generator can give people a place to start.
[Translation missing]
But I think that's just a super basic version of what we'll have in the future, which is high bandwidth interaction between you and the model as you're writing the prompt, where you're giving feedback.
Like, hey, this result wasn't what I wanted.
[Translation missing]
How can you change it to make it better?
你如何才能改进它呢？
And people will just grow more comfortable
人们会变得更加自如。
everything they do and this thing in particular?
他们所做的一切，尤其是这件事？
Yeah, I'm definitely working a lot with like meta prompts now and that's probably where I spend most of my time is like finding prompts that get the model to generate the kinds of outputs or queries or whatever that I want.
是的，我现在确实在进行很多元提示的工作，这大概是我花费时间最多的地方，就是寻找能够让模型生成我想要的输出或查询的提示。
On the question of where prompt engineering is going, I think this is a very hard question.
关于提示工程的未来，我认为这是一个非常困难的问题。
On the one hand, I'm like, maybe it's the case that as long as you will want the top.
一方面，我觉得，也许只要你想要最好的。
What are we doing when we prompt engineer?
我们在进行提示工程时究竟在做什么？
It's like what you said.
就像你说的那样。
I'm like, I'm not prompt engineering for anything that is easy for the model.
我并不是在为模型觉得简单的事情进行提示工程。
I'm doing it because I want to interact with a model that's extremely good.
我这么做是因为我想与一个非常优秀的模型互动。
And I want to always be finding the top 1%, top 0.1% of performance and all of the things that models can barely do.
我想要不断找到表现的前1%，前0.1%，以及模型几乎无法做到的所有事情。
Like sometimes I actually feel like I interact with a model like a step up from what everyone else interacts with for this reason, because I'm just so used to like eking out the top performance from models.
有时候我真的觉得我与模型的互动比其他人高一个档次，这就是原因，因为我习惯于从模型中榨取最佳性能。
What do you mean by a step up?
你说的高一个档次是什么意思？
As in like sometimes people will, I think that the everyday models that people interact with out in the world, it's like I'm interacting with a model that's like, I don't know how to describe it, but like definitely like an advanced version of that.
就是有时候人们会，我认为人们在世界上互动的日常模型，就像我正在与一个模型互动，我不知道怎么形容，但肯定是一个更高级的版本。
Like almost like a different model.
就像几乎是一个不同的模型。
Because they'll be like, oh, well, the models find this thing hard.
因为他们会说，哦，模型觉得这个事情很难。
And I'm like, that thing is trivial.
我说，那件事情是微不足道的。
And so it's like, I don't know, I have a sense that they're extremely capable, but I think that's because I'm just used to really drawing out those capabilities.
所以我不知道，我感觉它们非常有能力，但我想那是因为我已经习惯于真正挖掘这些能力。
But imagine that you're now in a world where, so I think the thing that feels like a transition point is the point at which the models,
但想象一下，现在你处于一个世界中，所以我觉得感觉像是转折点的是模型的时刻，
Let's suppose that they just get things at a human level on a given task, or even an above human level.
假设它们在某一任务上达到了人类水平，甚至超过人类水平。
They know more about the background of the task that you want than you do.
它们对你想要的任务的背景了解得比你还多。
What happens then?
那会发生什么？
Maybe prompting becomes something like, I explain to the model what I want, and it is kind of prompting me.
也许提示变成了这样的事情：我向模型解释我想要什么，而它在某种程度上是在提示我。
You know, because it's like, okay, well, do you mean like, actually, there's like four different concepts of this thing that you're talking about.
你知道，因为它会说，好的，实际上，你所说的这个事情有四个不同的概念。
Like, do you want me to use this one or that one?
你想让我使用这个还是那个？
Or by the way, I thought of some edge cases, because you said that it's going to be like a pandas data frame, but sometimes you do that and I get a JSONL and I just want to check what you want me to do there.
或者顺便说一下，我想到了几个边缘案例，因为你说它将是一个熊猫数据框，但有时你这样做，我得到的是JSONL，我只是想确认你希望我在那儿做什么。
Do you want me to flag if I get something that's not a data frame?
如果我得到的不是数据框，你希望我标记吗？
And so that could be a strange transition where it's just extremely good at receiving instructions but actually has to figure out what you want.
所以这可能是一个奇怪的过渡阶段，它非常擅长接收指令，但实际上必须弄清楚你想要什么。
And I don't know, I could see that being a kind of interesting switch.
我不知道，我可以看到这是一个有趣的转变。
Anecdotally, I've started having Claude interview me a lot more.
根据我的经验，我开始让Claude更多地采访我。
That is the specific way that I try to elicit information because, again, I find the hardest thing to be actually pulling the right set of information out of my brain and putting that into a prompt is the hard part to me.
这是我尝试引出信息的具体方式，因为，我发现，实际上从我的脑海中提取出正确的信息并将其放入提示中是我觉得最难的部分。
and not forgetting stuff.
并且不忘记东西。
And so like specifically asking Claude to like interview me and then turning that into a prompt is a thing that I have turned to a handful of times.
所以特别要求Claude来采访我，然后将其转化为提示，这是我转向的一种方法。
Yeah, it kind of reminds me of what people will talk about or if you listen to like designers talk about how they interact with the person who wants the design.
是的，这让我想起人们会谈论的，或者如果你听设计师谈论他们如何与想要设计的人互动。
So in some ways I'm like it's this switch from, you know, the temp agency person who comes and you know more about the task and everything that you want.
所以在某种程度上，我觉得这是一个转变，从你知道的临时机构的人来，你更了解这个任务以及你想要的一切。
So you give them the instructions and you explain what they should do in edge cases and all this kind of stuff versus when you have an expert that you're actually like consulting to do some work.
所以你给他们指令，解释他们在边缘案例中应该怎么做，所有这些事情，跟你有一个真正的专家在咨询你做一些工作。
So I think designers can get really frustrated because they know the space of design really well and they're like, yeah, okay, the client came to me and he just said, make me a poster, make it bold.
所以我认为设计师可能会感到非常沮丧，因为他们对设计领域非常熟悉，他们会说，是的，好吧，客户找我，他只是说，给我做一个海报，做得大胆一点。
And I'd have like, that means 7,000 things to me and I'm going to try and ask you some questions.
而我会觉得，这对我来说意味着7000种事情，我会试着问你一些问题。
So I could see it going from being like temp agency employee to being more like designer that you're hiring.
所以我可以看到它从像临时机构员工的角色变成更像是你雇佣的设计师。
And that's just like a flip in the relationship.
这只是关系的一个翻转。
I don't know if that's true, and I think both might continue, but I could see that being why people are like, oh, is prompt engineering going to not be a thing in the future?
我不知道这是否真实，我认为两者可能都会继续，但我可以看到这就是为什么人们会说，哦，提示工程在未来会不会不再存在？
Because for some domains, it might just not be.
因为对于某些领域来说，可能确实不会。
If the models are just so good that actually all they need to do is kind of like get the information from your brain, and then they can go do the task.
如果模型
Right, that's actually a really good analogy.
[Translation missing]
I mean, one common thread I'm pulling out of all your guys' responses here is that there seems to be a future in which this sort of elicitation from the user, drawing out that information, is going to become much more important, much more than it is right now.
And already, you guys are all starting to do it in a manual way in the future.
[Translation missing]
And in the enterprise side of things, maybe that looks like a
expansion off this prompt generating type of concept and things in the console where you're able to actually get more information from that enterprise customer so that they can write a better prompt.
[Translation missing]
In Clod, maybe it looks like less of just typing into a text box and more of this like guided interaction towards a finished product.
That's, yeah, that's, I think that's actually like a pretty compelling vision of future.
[Translation missing]
And I think that like the design analogy probably like really brings that home.
我觉得设计的类比真的很能说明这个问题。
I was thinking about how prompting now can be kind of like teaching, where it's like, you know, the empathy for the student, you're trying to think about how they think about things, you're really trying to show them, like, figure out where they're making a mistake.
我在想，现在的提示有点像教学，就像你需要对学生有同理心，试着理解他们的思维方式，真正想要帮助他们找出错误所在。
But the point that you're talking about, it's like, the skill almost becomes one of introspection, where you're thinking about what it is that you actually want.
但你提到的要点是，这种技能几乎变成了一种自省的能力，即思考你实际上想要的是什么。
And the model's trying to understand you, so it's like making yourself legible to the model versus trying to teach someone who's smarter than you.
模型试图理解你，这就像是让自己对模型变得可理解，而不是去教一个比你更聪明的人。
This is actually how I think of prompting now in a strange way.
这实际上是我现在对提示的看法，以一种奇怪的方式。
Like often my style of prompting, like there's various things that I do, but a common thing that's very, like a thing that philosophers will do is I'll define new concepts.
我常用的提示风格有很多种，但一个常见的做法是我会定义新的概念。
So, cause my thought is like, you have to put into words what you want.
因为我的想法是，你必须用语言清晰地表达出你想要的东西。
And sometimes what I want is fairly like nuanced, like the, what is a good chart?
有时候我想要的东西相当复杂，比如，什么是好的图表？
Or like usually, you know, like, I don't know, like how is it that you, when should you grade something as being correct or not?
或者，通常情况下，我不知道，什么时候应该将某个东西评定为正确或不正确？
And so there's some cases where I will just invent a concept and then be like, here's what I mean by the concept.
所以在某些情况下，我会创造一个概念，然后说，这就是我所指的概念。
Sometimes I'll do it in collaboration with Claude to get it to figure out what the concept is.
有时我会和Claude合作，帮助我理解这个概念。
Just because I'm trying to convey to it what's in my head.
只是因为我想要向它传达我脑海中的想法。
And right now the models aren't trying to do that with us unless you kind of prompt them to do so.
而现在模型并不会主动这样做，除非你引导它们去做。
And so in the future it might just be that they can elicit that from us rather than us having to do it for them.
所以未来可能只是它们能从我们这里引导出这些，而不是我们必须为它们去做。
But I think another thing that's kind of interesting, this is like a, people have sometimes asked me like, oh, where is like philosophy relevant to prompting?
但我觉得还有另一件有趣的事情，人们有时会问我，哲学与提示有什么关系。
And I actually think it's like very useful in a sense.
我实际上认为这在某种意义上是非常有用的。
So like a lot of, there is like a style of philosophy writing, and this is at least how I was taught how to write philosophy, where the idea is that in order to
就像有一种哲学写作风格，这至少是我学习哲学写作的方式，理念是为了
I think it's like an anti-bullshit device in philosophy basically, which is that your papers and what you write should be legible to a kind of educated layperson.
我认为这在哲学中是一个反对废话的工具，也就是说，你的论文和所写的东西应该对一种受过教育的外行人是可理解的。
Someone just finds your paper, they pick it up and they start reading it and they can understand everything.
有人随便找到你的论文，拿起来开始阅读，他们能理解一切。
Not everyone achieves this, but that's kind of the goal of the discipline, I guess, or at least this is at least what we kind of teach people.
并不是每个人都能做到这一点，但这大概是这个学科的目标，或者至少这是我们教给人们的。
And so I'm really used to this idea of when I'm writing, thinking about the kind of educated layperson who they're really smart, but they don't know anything about this topic.
所以我非常习惯在写作时考虑到这样一个受过教育的外行人，他们非常聪明，但对这个主题一无所知。
And that was just like years and years of writing text.
这就是多年来写作的经验。
of that form, and I think it was just really good for prompting, because I was like, oh, I'm used to this.
这种形式的写作，我觉得这对提示非常有帮助，因为我想，哦，我对此很熟悉。
I have an educated layperson who doesn't know anything about the topic, and what I need to do is I need to take extremely complex ideas, and I need to make them understand it.
我有一个对这个主题一无所知的受过教育的外行人，而我需要做的就是将极其复杂的想法转化为他们能够理解的内容。
I don't talk down to them.
我不以高人一等的态度对待他们。
I'm not inaccurate, but I need to phrase things in such a way that it's extremely clear to them what I mean, and prompting felt very similar, and actually, the training techniques we use are fascinating, or the things that you said where you say to a person,
我没有不准确，但我需要以一种极其清晰的方式表达我的意思，而提示给我的感觉非常相似，实际上，我们使用的训练技巧很有趣，或者你所说的，当你对一个人说，
just take that thing you said and write it down.
只需把你刚才说的那句话写下来。
I used to say that to students all the time.
我以前常常对学生这么说。
They'd write a paper and I was like, I don't quite get what you're saying here.
他们写一篇论文，我就会说，我不太明白你在说什么。
Can you just explain your argument to me?
你能给我解释一下你的论点吗？
They would give me an incredibly cogent argument and then I'd be like, can you just take that and write it down?
他们会给我一个非常清晰的论点，然后我就会说，你能把这个写下来吗？
And then if they did, that was often a great essay.
如果他们这样做，那通常会是篇好论文。
So it's really interesting that there's at least that similarity of just like,
所以有趣的是，至少有这种相似性，就像是，
taking things that are in your brain, analyzing them enough to feel like you fully understand them and could take any person off the street who's like a reasonable person and just like externalize your brain into them.
从你的脑海中提取东西，分析得足够清楚，以至于你感觉自己完全理解了，并且能够把任何一个街上的人，像一个理智的人一样，外化到他们身上。
And I feel like that's like the core of prompting.
我觉得这就是提示的核心。
That might be the best summary of how to prompt well I've ever heard.
这可能是我听过的关于如何好好提示的最佳总结。
In fact, I'm pretty sure it is.
实际上，我几乎可以肯定这是。
Externalize your brain.
外化你的思维。
And then we'll cut to them.
然后我们会切换到他们。
In education, in the thing is a really good way to describe the thing.
在教育中，描述这个事情的方式真的很好。
That was good.
这很好。
That's, I think, a great way to wrap this conversation.
我觉得这是结束这个对话的一个优秀方式。
Thank you guys, this was great.
谢谢大家，这真是太棒了。